<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Smart Grid Use Cases – Use Cases</title><link>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/</link><description>Recent content in Use Cases on Smart Grid Use Cases</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: ACCEPT</title><link>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/accept/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/accept/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: BRIDGE</title><link>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/bridge/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/bridge/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: CROSSBOW</title><link>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/crossbow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/crossbow/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: E-LAND</title><link>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/e-land/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/e-land/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: OneNet</title><link>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/onenet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/onenet/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: PARITY</title><link>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/parity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/parity/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: X-FLEX</title><link>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/x-flex/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/x-flex/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: PlatOne</title><link>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/platone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/platone/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: RS-TF</title><link>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/rs-tf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/rs-tf/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: MAESHA</title><link>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/maesha/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/maesha/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="1-description-of-the-use-case">1. Description of the Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="11-name-of-the-use-case">1.1. Name of the Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>ID&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Area /Domain(s)/Zone(s)&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name of the Use Case&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Area: Energy system, Domain: Transmission, DER, Customer Premises, Zones: Operation, Market,&lt;/td>
&lt;td>MAESHA&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="12-version-management">1.2. Version Management&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Version No.&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Date&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name of author(s)&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Changes&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Approval status&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1.0&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2021-10-31T00:00:00&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Andraž Andolšek (cyberGRID), Christoph Gutschi (cyberGRID), Marjolaine Farré (Trialog), Elchaysse Soudjae (Electricité de Mayotte),&lt;/td>
&lt;td>First version&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Final&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="13-scope-and-objectives-of-use-case">1.3. Scope and Objectives of Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Scope&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The scope of this use case is to examine the use of flexibility to restore system frequency to its nominal value of 50 Hz.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Objective(s)&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The main objective of this use case is to stabilize the electricity grid of the islands by establishing balancing services. Implementing the balancing services framework will help system operators to maintain the equilibrium between consumption and generation while minimizing the frequency deviation from the nominal values.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Related business case(s)&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Linked to “Voltage control” UC (UC2) as potential conflicts within flexibility products could appear.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="14-narrative-of-use-case">1.4. Narrative of Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Short description&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This high-level use case describes different scenarios incl. all required steps for the implementation of a tender based frequency control system. The UC differentiates between FCR (frequency containment reserve) and FRR (frequency restoration reserve) services. The explained approach is technology agnostic and supports any kind of flexibility resource, that can meet the technical requirements for balancing service provision. A common approach to handle different technologies for flexibility provision (industrial demand response, residential demand response aggregated by a VPP, smart charging of electric vehicles, aggregation of renewables (PV) via a VPP, battery energy storage, power-to-hydrogen electrolyser) is explained.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The scope of the use case includes dimensioning of balancing service reserves for an islanding system, prequalification of suitable distributed energy assets and intermediary platforms (Virtual Power Plants, VPPs), tendering and contracting balancing services, balancing service activation, monitoring, validation, and remuneration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All periodic communication between the system operator and the market participants, like bidding, monitoring and activation is organized via a Flexibility Management and Trading Platform (FMTP).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The use case focuses on the situation on the Island of Mayotte and aims to adapt to the historically grown infrastructure and processes, but also takes into account updates of the system operators SCADA in the near future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Complete description&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introduction to balancing services for frequency control&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The system operator Electricité de Mayotte (EDM), responsible for grid operation and supply of electric energy, needs to maintain the network frequency within a narrow bandwidth (+300 / -200 mHz) around 50 Hz. Frequency deviation is a consequence of an imbalance between generation (feed-in to the grid) and consumption (extraction from the grid) including losses of the grid itself. These imbalances are mainly caused by unpredictable fluctuations of the load (low impact on the grid frequency), general imprecisions in the load forecasting that cause improper generation schedules (medium impact) or rare fault-induced disconnection of entire branches or substations or even unexpected loss of generation (high impact). Until now, the electricity system in Mayotte relied on fast adaption of the generation of spinning diesel engines to balance the load fluctuations. These diesel engines also cover for the main generation schedule.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The mechanisms to maintain the grid frequency within a narrow bandwidth can be distinguished between three main types of control, as shown in Figure 24. After an incident like the unexpected outage of a generator, the imbalance between load and generation causes an immediate decrease of the grid frequency, which is mainly limited by the kinetic energy stored in spinning machines (synchronous inertia). The higher the inertia of the rotating machines connected to the grid, the lower the gradient of frequency change (Df/Dt), also known as rate of change in frequency (ROCOF). The frequency stabilization by inertia is a physical effect, responding spontaneously to any frequency gradient and acting in both directions. New generations of inverters can provide a frequency gradient dependent feed-in (with only a minor time lag), which can be considered as “virtual inertia”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[See figure &amp;ldquo;Overview of phases of frequency control after a major outage&amp;rdquo; below]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The frequency containment reserve (FCR), also known as primary control, provides a variable feed-in linearly depending on the deviation of the frequency (Df) from the target value of 50 Hz. FCR is required to act very fast. The required full activation time (FAT) is determined by the considered maximum imbalance (e.g., due to loss of the largest generation unit in the system), the maximum allowed frequency deviation and the typical inertia of the system. FCR is a very fast service that requires frequency measurements and control logic directly at the providing asset, usually a generator or battery. Some loads controlled by power electronics might also be feasible to provide FCR. Usually, FCR is a symmetric service that acts in both directions. The linear function of FCR power only depending on the frequency deviation enables a fast response to limit the frequency deviation but does not allow to bring the frequency back to the target value.
Some transmission system operators (TSO), e.g., in the NORDPOOL, differentiate between Frequency Containment Reserve for Normal Operation (FCR-N) and Frequency Containment Reserve for Disturbances (FCR-D). FCR-N is a symmetric service providing upregulation and downregulation with a linear characteristic while FCR-D differentiate between upward (increase feed-in or decrease consumption) and downward (decrease feed-in or increase consumption) regulation. FCR-D is only activated after exceeding a threshold value of frequency deviation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[See figure &amp;ldquo;FCR architecture overview&amp;rdquo; below]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The frequency restoration reserve FRR is managed by the system operator (SO) using the automatic generation control (AGC). The AGC calculates setpoints for multiple balancing providing assets (generators, batteries but also fast and precisely controllable loads like electrolyser). After reception of the setpoint the assets will adapt the power output within a defined FAT that may be longer than required for FCR. The AGC aims to bring the system frequency back to the target value. FRR requires reliable communication between the central AGC and the distributed assets. FRR can be divided into positive products for upward control and negative products for downward control. European TSO differentiate between faster, automatically controlled reserves (aFRR), that follow to instantaneous setpoints, and slower reserves that might be manually controlled (mFRR) and follow to received schedules.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[See figure &amp;ldquo;FRR architecture overview&amp;rdquo; below]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>FCR and FRR provision in Europe usually require active power measurements with high precision (e.g., 0.5% error class) and submission of data points to the SO in short intervals (e.g., 1-2 s) for the purpose of real-time monitoring of provision and ex-post validation of the provided services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additional Emergency measures will be activated in case that the frequency regulation system failed, and the frequency deviation exceeds defined thresholds. Emergency measure can include load shedding, disconnection of large, robust consumers or disconnection of generators. The rules for frequency protection devices to disconnect sensible assets in case of high frequency deviations must be defined accordingly to support system frequency stabilization and to avoid negative feedback on the frequency control mechanisms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Context&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The rising number of PV power plants to be installed and connected to the main grid in Mayotte may increase the difficulty of frequency control as the production is highly dependent on weather conditions challenging to forecast (e.g., a passing cloud leads to a decline in PV production) which may increase the imbalances between generation and consumption. With increasing number of PV generation, partly replacing diesel generators the ratio of spinning machines in the system will be reduced which has negative impact on the synchronous inertia. To avoid reaching low frequency thresholds leading to load shedding (48.5 Hz, 48 Hz and 47.5 Hz), the French Energy Regulatory Commission (CRE) granted an exemption to EDM to operate the grid at a higher frequency. The current mean frequency value is thus of 50.15 Hz, higher than the 50 Hz stipulated in the EU Electricity Network code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main balancing service to cope with the frequency deviation currently applied on the island of Mayotte is the “primary reserve” (covering FCR and FRR), which is estimated at 15% of the daily demand and mainly supported by the EDM diesel generation sets of Longoni and Badamiers. The generators are limited to operate at 80-85% of their maximal capacity. For the past few years, the primary reserve hadn’t exceeded 8 MW, but this will change soon with an expected rising demand and RES integration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To stabilize the frequency in the island and ease the penetration of renewable energy, the French Energy Regulatory Commission CRE launched a call for tender to install a battery for frequency control in July 2018. This 4 MW/2 MWh battery should be installed and be ready to operate in October 2021. Following this installation, the exemption (of higher system frequency) should disappear for the time-being. It is estimated that further investments will be needed to fulfil the requirements that are foreseen in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the goals when considering the frequency use case is to find a way for moving from the energy assets providing frequency services with the help of fossil fuel to assets using renewable energy sources (RES) and Battery Energy Storage Systems (BESS). To further reduce the primary reserve provided by the EDM’s diesel generation sets new sources for providing frequency regulation services are needed to have a direct impact on reduction of CO2 emissions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main challenges when implementing the frequency control framework are related to the identification of sufficient assets from RES to reduce the required capacity of fossil fueled generators that are capable to provide similar reliable frequency services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The use case describes the interactions between the main actors and platforms but doesn’t discuss the details of the balancing products. The details of the designed balancing products will be defined Deliverable D4.1 Report detailing the energy market framework and specific product design details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the MAESHA project, it has been decided to examine how different flexibility sources could support the frequency control on the island:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>•Industrial Demand Response&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Industry’s main purpose is manufacturing of goods or provision of other services. Some industrial assets are additionally able to provide a certain help to the system operator by adjusting their internal manufacturing process and thus increase or decrease the consumption for the time being (load shifting) and help minimizing the frequency deviation. Such industrial energy assets usually have some restrictions, such as limited duration of delivery (e.g., max 4 h), poor controllability (e.g., ON-OFF operation), or can provide such action only at a certain time of the day or year. Therefore, industrial demand response is not considered as a primary source for providing balancing services to the power grid, but they may serve as secondary source for additional support when other services are already fully activated (e.g., for emergency measures).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• Residential Demand Response managed by a virtual power plant (VPP)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Residential customers may have flexible loads that end-users do not necessarily need instantaneously to ensure their comfort, e.g., air-conditioning units and electric heating, but also dishwashers, washing machines, cloth dryers, etc. Optimally controlling the on/off times of these devices, considering local frequency deviations, can help in ensuring the frequency stability. Depending on the characteristics of the device, the activation time and activation duration differ. Heat pumps or air conditioning units can be used for frequency response, considering the heat storage capacity of the building or heat storage in a hot water tank. The activation duration depends upon the stored heat capacity in the building or the tank and the comfort requirements of the end-users. These units can be activated very fast (remote switch-off) but their availability is difficult to forecast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• Smart Charging of electric vehicles (EV) and vehicle to grid (V2G)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Smart charging of EV can be a source of consumption flexibility and theoretically be used even for balancing services. The challenges for provision of FRR by an EV are linked to the prediction of the charging process’ time and duration as well as the limited hours per day, when EV charging can be used for load shifting. Nevertheless, the forecasting of consumption and flexibility becomes easier on a fleet of EVs, as such an aggregate of a higher number of EV’s can provide ancillary services reliably using a minor share of the predicted consumption. Load reduction in EV charging can be achieved by reducing the charging power (e.g., switch from 3-phase to 1-phase charging) of a certain number of vehicles. Advanced fleet management might also allow downward services by increasing the charging power during the requested period. Feed-in of energy stored in the EV’s batteries (V2G) will been investigated as another possibility of upward regulation by EVs but comes with practical drawbacks like possible reduction of battery lifetime and the need for bidirectional inverters. Due to the nature of the fleet management and lower frequency of data acquisition, EV charging will be preferably applied for mFRR than for aFRR or FCR like frequency services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• Virtual Power Plant (VPP) aggregating RES&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The variability of renewable energy sources, such as wind and solar, are causing continuous, small frequency deviations due to their hard to predict short-term dynamics and their lack of synchronous inertia to stabilize the frequency during disturbances. Lowering the output of PV plants (downward regulation) during high frequency periods can support frequency stabilization. If PVs are operated below their maximal inverter power, PV plants can inject additional power into the grid with different activation times, ranging from seconds to minutes during low frequency periods (upward regulation). The latter will result in a reduction of overall generation or require the installation of PV batteries. The activation duration depends on the amount of reserve kept for upward frequency response and will be the result of a cost-benefit analysis, where the outcome depends on the remuneration of the different frequency response products compared to the value of electric energy fed-in by PV. In the last years, much development effort has been made on virtual inertia provided by PV and wind power, which might become state-of-the-art within the next decades.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• Battery Energy Storage System&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By supplying or absorbing power in response to deviations from the nominal frequency and imbalances between supply and demand, the rapid response of a BESS will provide a frequency stabilizing services. The fast response capability of BESS allows them to participate in all kinds of frequency response (e.g., FCR, FRR) or even a fast or enhanced frequency response markets (activation in less than 5 s). The BESS will also provide virtual inertia by modulating active power as a function of the ROCOF. The duration of the service provision will be determined by the SoC. BESS providing ancillary services will require an additional charge management to maintain the state of charge (SOC) within predefined limits (e.g., 30%&amp;lt;SOC&amp;lt;70%) in order to ensure the continuous availability of upward and downward regulation ability. Load management (consumption or feed-in) is based on schedules and should be communicated with the SO, e.g., via an intraday program. The BESS should be able to provide multiple balancing services and perform load management in parallel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>• Power-to-Hydrogen system&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Proton Exchange Membrane (PEM) electrolysers have the capability of modifying their load rapidly with very high ramps rates (i.e., within seconds) and within a wide operational range up to the nominal power. This flexibility can be utilized for large range of frequency regulation (e.g., FCR, aFRR, mFRR). Despite the hydrogen storage capacity, there is no limit in the duration of the service as the service is provided by reducing/increasing the load of the electrolyser.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These DER provide their flexibility to the SO via the FMTP, as indicated in Figure below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[See figure &amp;ldquo;Architecture overview for frequency control in MAESHA&amp;rdquo; below]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Functions&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This Use Case relies on the following functions:
•Asset contraction and technical preparation, incl. pre-qualification
•Detection of frequency deviations
•Evaluation of flexibility available from different assets or via intermediate platforms
•Contracting balancing service products
•Calculation of setpoints by the AGC of the SO
•Flexibility activation through the Flexibility Management and Trading Platform (FMTP)
•Monitoring of service provision
•Settlement process to remunerate flexibility activation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This Use Case supports a technology-agnostic approach for provision of balancing services by central or decentralized energy assets. In the MAESHA project, the following technologies are aimed to be investigated in the scope of the use case demonstration:
•Detection of frequency deviations, central by SO or decentral by the DER
•Frequency regulation by industrial DR
•Frequency regulation by residential DR via VPP
•Frequency regulation by Smart charging/V2G
•Frequency regulation by RES via VPP
•Frequency regulation by BESS
•Frequency regulation by P2H system&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="15-key-performance-indicatiors-kpi">1.5. Key Performance Indicatiors (KPI)&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>ID&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Reference to mentioned use case objectives&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Frequency range before and after the project&lt;/td>
&lt;td>From [49.6;50.6] to [49.8;50.3] Hz&lt;/td>
&lt;td>/,&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="16-use-case-conditions">1.6. Use case conditions&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Assumptions&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>MAESHA&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Prerequisites&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>MAESHA&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="17-further-information-to-the-use-case-for-classificationmapping">1.7. Further information to the use case for classification/mapping&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Relation to other use cases&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Level of depth&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Prioritisation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Obligatory. This UC should be demonstrated under real-life conditions&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Generic, regional or national relation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Regional relation&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Nature of the use cases&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Technical and business UC&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Further keywords for classification&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Balancing services, load-frequency control, demand response, flexibility, distributed energy resources (DER)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="18-general-remarks">1.8. General remarks&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>General remarks&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="2-diagrams-of-use-case">2. Diagrams of Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="BusinessLayer_FrequencyControlUC.png" alt="SGAM Business layer of the frequency control use case-specific architecture">
&lt;img src="FunctionLayer_FrequencyControlUC.png" alt="SGAM Function layer of the frequency control use case-specific architecture">
&lt;img src="FrequencyControlPhasesAfterMajorOutage.png" alt="Overview of phases of frequency control after a major outage">
&lt;img src="FCR_Architecture.png" alt="FCR achitecture overview">
&lt;img src="FRR_Architecture.png" alt="FRR achitecture overview">
&lt;img src="FrequencyControlArchi_OverviewMAESHA.png" alt="Architecture overview for frequency control in MAESHA">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="3-technical-details">3. Technical Details&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="31-actors">3.1. Actors&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Type&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Further information specific to this Use Case&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>TSO&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Business actor&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Transmission System Operator&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Flexibility provider&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Business actor&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Generic presentation of the energy asset capable of providing flexibility on request (balancing service provider)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Residential prosumer&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Business actor&lt;/td>
&lt;td>A residential party that consumers electricity (Flexibility Provider)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Industrial prosumer&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Business actor&lt;/td>
&lt;td>An industrial party that consumes electricity (Flexibility Provider)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>SCADA&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Logical actor&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Supervisory Control and Data Acquisition – a supervisory computerized system that gathers and processes data and applies operational controls for transmission side systems used to control dispersed assets&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>AGC&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Logical actor&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Automatic gain control. Process to determine the amount of power needed to bring back the frequency to the nominal values.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Intermediate platform&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Logical actor&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Platform that aggregates flexibility energy assets (virtual power plant, EV charging management platform)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Small-scale virtual power plant&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Logical actor&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This is a type of Intermediate platforms. Software platform that aggregates the flexibility of residential prosumers and PV power plants&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Large-scale virtual power plant&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Logical actor&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This is a type of Intermediate platforms. Software platform that aggregates the flexibility of industrial energy assets and BESS&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>EV charging management platform&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Logical actor&lt;/td>
&lt;td>A platform that manages and aggregates the charging power of multiple EV charging stations&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>FMTP&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Logical actor&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Flexibility Management and Trading Platform&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Distributed Energy Resource (DER)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Asset&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Generic presentation of the energy asset providing flexibility&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>PV power plant&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Asset&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Renewable energy source able to provide flexibility of feed-in&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Battery&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Asset&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy storage system capable of providing different services to the grid&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>P2H system&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Asset&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System to convert electricity (optimally from RES) into hydrogen that can be stored to use it eventually for different purposes (feedstock, electricity production, fuel)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Diesel generator&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Asset&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Synchronous generators&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>EV charging station&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Device&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="32-references">3.2. References&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>References Type&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Reference&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Status&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Impact on Use Case&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Organistaor / Organisation&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Link&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Operational guidelines&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Operational guidelines from ENTSO-E&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Final&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Medium&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://eepublicdownloads.entsoe.eu/clean-documents/pre2015/publications/entsoe/Operation_Handbook/Policy_1_final.pdf">https://eepublicdownloads.entsoe.eu/clean-documents/pre2015/publications/entsoe/Operation_Handbook/Policy_1_final.pdf&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Operational guidelines&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Operational guidelines from the French government&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Final&lt;/td>
&lt;td>High&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://codes.droit.org/PDF/Code%20de%20l'%C3%A9nergie.pdf">https://codes.droit.org/PDF/Code%20de%20l'%C3%A9nergie.pdf&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Role model&lt;/td>
&lt;td>ENTSO-E Role model&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Version 2020-01&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Medium&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://www.entsoe.eu/digital/cim/role-models/#harmonised-electricity-role-model">https://www.entsoe.eu/digital/cim/role-models/#harmonised-electricity-role-model&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="4-step-by-step-analysis-of-use-case">4. Step by Step Analysis of Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="41-overview-of-scenarios">4.1. Overview of Scenarios&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Primary Actor&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Triggering Event&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Pre-Condition&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Post-Condition&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Sc1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Frequency reserve requirements&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Calculating the amount of FCR and FRR needed&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Frequency reserve requirements&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Sc2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Detection of the frequency issues - FCR&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Detection of the frequency deviations locally on the site of the flexibility provider&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Detection of the frequency issues - FCR&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Sc3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Detection of the frequency issues - FRR&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Detection of the frequency deviations centrally in the SCADA&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Detection of the frequency issues - FRR&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Sc4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Contracting balancing service products&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Contractual obligations between the SO (EDM) and the flexibility providers&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Contracting balancing service products&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Sc5&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Flexibility activation through local controller - FCR&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Activation of the flexibility providers automatically using its local controller&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Flexibility activation through local controller - FCR&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Sc6&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Flexibility activation through the Flexibility Management and Trading Platform (FMTP) - FRR&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Activation of the flexibility providers automatically using centralized platform - FMTP&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Flexibility activation through the Flexibility Management and Trading Platform (FMTP) - FRR&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Sc7&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Settlement process to remunerate flexibility activation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Validation and settlement of the activation responses&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Settlement process to remunerate flexibility activation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Sc8&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Frequency control by flexibility provider&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The process of flexibility provision by the flexibility provider&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Frequency control by flexibility provider&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Notes&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="42-steps--scenarios">4.2. Steps – Scenarios&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Frequency reserve requirements&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Periodically (yearly)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Define desired conditions for grid frequency&lt;/td>
&lt;td>In a phase of mid-term planning, the SO defines the frequency control strategy, incl. nominal (target) frequency value, frequency bandwidth for operation and frequency thresholds for emergency actions&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Periodically (yearly)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Collect data of the power system&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Collect the data to describe the power system (system model), historic measurements (load, frequency) and events (fault statistics)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Periodically (yearly)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Mid-term &amp;amp; long-term forecasts&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The SO generates mid-term and long-term forecasts of the development of consumption and generation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Periodically (yearly)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Define design scenarios&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The SO identifies critical situations (e.g., yearly peak load, separation of parts of the grid, etc.) and defines design scenarios comprising all possible critical situations.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>5&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Periodically (yearly)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Calculate the required amount of flexibility- balancing reserve needed on the island - FRR&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The SO assesses the amount of flexibility (FCR, FRR balancing reserve) required to perform the load-frequency control of the power system of the geographical islands.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>6&lt;/td>
&lt;td>St5 finished&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Define balancing service products&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Based on the required amount of flexibility the SO defines appropriate balancing products&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Detection of the frequency issues - FCR&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Periodically (interval of 1s of faster)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Measure the network frequency&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy assets (central assets or DER) capable of providing FCR reserve are equipped with an accurate frequency meter to continuously measure frequency of the point of grid connection in real-time&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>New frequency measurement available&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Submit the measured frequency to the local controller&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The measured frequency must be sent to the local controller capable of receiving freq. measurements in real-time&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>When freq. measurements arrive to the local controller&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Calculate frequency deviation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>An algorithm on the PLC compares the measured frequency with the target value and calculates the deviation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Detection of the frequency issues - FRR&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Continuously&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Measure grid frequency&lt;/td>
&lt;td>An accurate (central) frequency meter located in a major substation (e.g., Longoni, Badamiers) measures frequency of the grid in real-time&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Continuously&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Receive frequency measurement&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The measured frequency is received by the AGC embedded in the SCADA.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Frequency measurement received by AGC&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Measured frequency is stored and available for processing&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The frequency measurements need to be persisted and available in real time and for later analysis. The SCADA (where AGC is embedded) saved the measurements in a database.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REPORT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Frequency measurement received by AGC&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Calculate the frequency deviation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Calculate the difference between the current measured frequency and the define nominal (target) frequency (e.g., 50 Hz)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>5&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Frequency deviation calculated&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Calculate the new FRR setpoint&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Based on the actual frequency deviation and its change in time the control algorithm calculates the new FRR setpoint&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CHANGE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Contracting balancing service products&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>After definition of technical require-ments&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Publish technical and market rules for balancing services&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The SO publishes the document describing the balancing services, their technical and administrative requirements and tendered products.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>After reception of balancing service rules&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Flexibility providers prepare for participation in balancing services&lt;/td>
&lt;td>(3rd party) flexibility providers able to fulfil the SO’s requirements prepare for participation via the FMTP, directly or by aggregation via an intermediate platform (e.g., analyse available flexible power, identify suitable flexibility services and products, fulfil technical requirements). Finally, the flexibility provider or aggregator requests the prequalification of the DER (if directly connected to the FMTP).&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>After reception of tender announcement&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Aggregators prepare for participation in balancing services&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Aggregators prepare for balancing service provision, implementing the technical requirements and establishing contracts with flexibility providers. Finally, the aggregator requests the prequalification of the intermediate platform.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>SO received request for prequalification&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Prequalify flexibility provider&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The SO and flexibility provider (and aggregator if involved) conduct a series of tests to confirm the technical and administrative capability of the DER (and intermediate platform if involved) to provide the balancing services according to the SO’s requirements. The step is finalized by issuing the confirmation of prequalification by the SO.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>5&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Periodically (yearly, monthly, weekly, or daily)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Publish tender for balancing services&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The SO details the balancing market products and starts a tendering process and informs all prequalified flexibility providers about the tender&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>6&lt;/td>
&lt;td>St5 finalized&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Submit balancing services bids&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The prequalified flexibility providers forecast the available power for the tendered balancing service products and calculate the costs of service provision. Then the most suitable balancing products are identified and balancing service bids are submitted via FMTP.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>7&lt;/td>
&lt;td>SO received bid for balancing service provision&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Contract balancing services&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The SO selects the most favourable bids for flexibility service provision according to the tendering rules and informs the flexibility providers about acceptance or rejection of their bids via the FMTP. The acceptance of a balancing service bid is equivalent to a legal contract between SO and flexibility provider.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Flexibility activation through local controller - FCR&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Reception of FCR bid acceptance&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Enable FCR service&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The FCR functionality is unlocked via the PLC of the DER during the timespan defined in the accepted FCR bid.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FCR provision enabled&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Calculate FCR setpoint&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The PLC calculates the FCR setpoint depending on the frequency deviation (calculated on-site and in real time, see scenario 2) based on an algorithm defined by the SO; e.g., a linear curve PFCR=f(Df)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FCR setpoint calculated (continuously, e.g., 1s interval)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Follow new FCR setpoint&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The DER adapts the active power feed-in (or consumption) according to the FCR setpoint within the required FAT.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Continuously (e.g., 1s interval)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Send monitoring data to FMTP&lt;/td>
&lt;td>As long as the FCR service provision is enabled (timespan of the accepted FCR bid), the PLC sends monitoring data to the FMTP, where it is forwarded to the AGC)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>5&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Continuously&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Validate FCR provision&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The AGC receives the FCR monitoring data and compares the measurements with the expected behaviour.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>6&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FCR malperformance detected&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Inform flexibility provider about malperformance&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The SO informs the flexibility provider about the FCR malperformance and orders immediate correction of the behaviour&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REPORT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>7&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FCR validation report received&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Remedy FCR malperformance&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The flexibility provider updates the DER control algorithms in order to remedy the FCR malperformance and to provide the FCR service according to technical specifications.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Flexibility activation through the Flexibility Management and Trading Platform (FMTP) - FRR&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Reception of FRR bid acceptance&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Enable FRR service&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The FRR functionality is unlocked on the intermediate platform and/or the PLC of the DER during the timespan defined in the accepted FRR bid. The PLC starts waiting to receive activation requests from the FMTP or intermediate platform.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>New FRR setpoint available&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Dispatch balancing assets&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The new FRR setpoint is dispatched between central balancing assets (diesel engines operated by the SO) and distributed balancing assets (DER operated by third party).&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3a&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Central assets’ FRR setpoint updated&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Receive new FRR setpoints&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Central balancing assets (operated by the SO) receive their new individual setpoint&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3b&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Decentral assets’ FRR setpoint updated&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Receive new FRR setpoints&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The updated FRR setpoint is received by the FMTP platform.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FMTP received a new FRR setpoint&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FMTP dispatches contracted flexibility providers&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The FMTP distributes the received FRR setpoint between the contracted flexibility providers (DERs or intermediate platforms) based on predefined rules (pro-rata or according to merit order), and submits the activation requests (direct setpoint or activation schedule).&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>5&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Intermediate platform receives activation request&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Intermediate platform distributes activation requests&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The intermediate platform disaggregates the received activation request and forwards the setpoints to the connected DER, which previously indicated availability.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>6&lt;/td>
&lt;td>DER received the activation request&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FRR provision by DER&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The DER changes its generation or consumption according to the received setpoint within the required FAT (details see scenario 8).&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>7&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Continuously (e.g., in 2s interval)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Send monitoring data to intermediate platform&lt;/td>
&lt;td>As long as the FRR service provision is enabled (timespan of the accepted FRR bid), the DER sends monitoring data to the intermediate platform.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>8&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Continuously (e.g., in 2s interval)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Send monitoring data to AGC&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The intermediate platform receives monitoring data from the connected DER and aggregates the values. The aggregated values are sent to the FMTP. Alternatively, large DER send monitoring data directly to the FMTP, without aggregation via an intermediate platform.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>9a&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Continuously&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Validate FRR provision&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The FMTP receives the FRR monitoring data and compares the measurements with the expected behaviour.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>9b&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Yearly&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Validate FRR provision&lt;/td>
&lt;td>In case of doubts, the SO compares FRR monitoring data with (public) meter readings.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>10&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FRR malperformance detected&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Inform flexibility provider about malperformance&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The SO informs the flexibility provider about the FRR malperformance and orders immediate correction of the behaviour.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REPORT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>11&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FRR validation report received&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Remedy FRR malperformance&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The flexibility provider updates the DER control algorithms in order to remedy the FRR malperformance and to provide the FRR service according to technical specifications.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Settlement process to remunerate flexibility activation&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Daily&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Process monitoring data&lt;/td>
&lt;td>In the morning hours the energy activated during the previous day is calculated individually for each balancing service contract (accepted bid).&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>After completing previous step&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Accounting of balancing service provision&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The activated energy and reserved capacity (provided by the aggregator or flexibility provider) is accounted per accepted bid and summarized by flexibility provider.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Monthly&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Remuneration of flexibility service provision&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The daily remuneration of balancing service provision is summarized for the entire past month and remunerated to each flexibility provider&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Frequency control by flexibility provider&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Daily&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Forecast flexible capacity for upcoming tender period&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The flexibility provider forecasts the amount and costs of the balancing service provision for the next tender period.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Previous step finalized&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Aggregator receives flexibility forecast&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The aggregator receives the flexible capacity &amp;amp; cost forecasts of all contracted flexibility providers (DERs) and creates a merit order of flexibility.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Previous step finalized&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Participation in balancing service tender&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The aggregator participates in the balancing service tender, creates bids and submits the bids to the FMTP. (See scenario 4)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Bid acceptance message received&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Flexibility reservation request&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The aggregator informs the connected DER about required flexibility reservation for the next product period and the conditions for balancing service provision.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>5&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Flexibility reservation request received&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Flexibility reservation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The DER reserves the requested flexibility for the product period.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>6&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Continuously&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Real-time flexibility calculation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The DER calculates the actual flexibility bandwidth in real time and reports the values to the intermediary platform.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>7&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Continuously&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Listen to incoming setpoints&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The PLC receives a setpoint to start an activation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>8&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Activation setpoint received by DER&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Start activation program&lt;/td>
&lt;td>After receiving a new setpoint (see (see scenario 6), the PLC of the DER initiates the activation program (ramp-up) in order to meet the setpoint received from the intermediary platform within the FAT.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>9&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Continuously&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Listen to incoming setpoints&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The PLC receives a new setpoint to change the power of an activation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>10&lt;/td>
&lt;td>New activation setpoint received by DER&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Change activation program&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The PLC of the DER updates the activation program (ramp-up) in order to meet the new setpoint within the FAT.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>11&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Continuously&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Listen to incoming setpoints&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The PLC receives a setpoint of 0 MW to end the ongoing activation.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>12&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Activation end received by DER&lt;/td>
&lt;td>End activation program&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The PLC of the DER initiates the end activation program (ramp-down) in order and the balancing energy provision within the FAT.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>13&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Continuously (e.g., 2s interval)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Send monitoring data&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The DER processes the actual measurements and sends the required monitoring data to the intermediary platform.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="5-information-exchanged">5. Information Exchanged&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information exchanged ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Information&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirement&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="6-requirements-optional">6. Requirements (optional)&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Category Identifier&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>mRID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Req_ID&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Req_Name&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Frequency control&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Identifier&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>mRID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-01-01&lt;/td>
&lt;td>frequency band-width and emergency thresholds&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Predefined bandwidth of allowed system frequency, including target value (50 Hz) and thresholds for initiating emergency measures&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-01-02&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System model&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Model of the power system supporting dynamic analyses&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-01-03&lt;/td>
&lt;td>historic measurements&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Historic timeseries of measured generation, consumption and system frequency&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-01-04&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Fault statistics&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Statistics of faults in the power system that are relevant for balancing reserve dimensioning&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-01-05&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Consumption forecasts&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Mid-term (timeseries) of the total consumption&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-01-06&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Design scenarios&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Expected critical situations (e.g., yearly peak load, separation of parts of the grid, etc.) relevant for balancing reserve dimensioning&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-01-07&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Required amount of balancing reserve&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Required number of balancing reserves to ensure a stable operation of the power system, (e.g., 99.975% reliability)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-01-08&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Balancing products and requirements&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Definition of balancing products and requirements comprising: products (duration, min. bid size, direction, tolerances)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-02-01&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Network frequency&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Actual measurements of network frequency measured on-site by DER&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-02-02&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Frequency deviation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Actual frequency deviation detected on-site at DER&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-03-01&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Grid Frequency&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Actual measurements of grid frequency centrally acquired by SO&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-03-02&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Frequency deviation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Actual frequency deviation detected centrally by SO&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-03-03&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Updated FRR setpoint&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Actual FRR setpoint calculated by AGC, sum for all assets participating in FRR service provision&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-04-01&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Balancing services rules&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The document describing the rules for participation in balancing services, their technical and administrative requirements and tendered products, as well as the prequalification procedure&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-04-02&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Request for prequalification of DER&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The flexibility provider (DER operator) applies for the prequalification for the balancing service participation.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-04-03&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Request for prequalification of platform&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The aggregator (intermediate platform operator) applies for the prequalification for the balancing service participation.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-04-04&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Confirmation of prequalification&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The SO confirms the successful prequalification of a DER or platform. Confirmation may need to be renewed after an expiry period.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-04-05&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Rules and schedules of balancing service tender&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The SO publishes the rules and schedules of balancing service tender, including description of tendered balancing service products.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-04-06&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Balancing service bid document&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The aggregator or flexibility provider participates in the tender for balancing services by submitting one or multiple binding bids. Bids contains ID of bidder, date, timespan, product ID, power, capacity price, energy price.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-04-07&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Balancing service bid acceptance&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The SO informs the bidders about acceptance or rejection of the bids submitted in the tender.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-05-01&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FCR provision enabled&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The (PLC of the) DER enabled the FCR functionality and starts detecting the frequency deviations.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-05-02&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FCR setpoint&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FCR setpoint calculated on-site by PLC (DER)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-05-03&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FCR monitoring data&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The FCR monitoring data includes local measurements of frequency, active power, calculated setpoint, actual FCR provision. It is submitted in short intervals (e.g., of 2s).&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-05-04&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FCR validation report&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The FCR validation report summarizes the quality of FCR service provision of a flexibility provider.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-06-01&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FRR provision enabled&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The (PLC of the) DER enabled the FCR functionality and starts listening for incoming setpoints&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-06-02&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FRR setpoints for central balancing assets&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FRR setpoints for central balancing assets (controlled by the SO)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-06-03&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FRR setpoint for DER&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FRR setpoints for DER (controlled by 3rd party flexibility providers)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-06-04&lt;/td>
&lt;td>FRR Activation requests&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-06-05&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Individual FRR setpoints&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Individual FRR setpoints for DER controlled via an intermedia platform&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-06-06&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Individual FRR monitoring data&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Monitoring data of individual DER, which is sent to an intermediate platform. Datapoints: active power, baseline, setpoint, FRR activation, control bandwidth&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-06-07&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Aggregated FRR monitoring data&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Aggregated monitoring data of a pool of DER (managed by an intermediary platform), which is sent to the FMTP. Datapoints: active power, baseline, setpoint, FRR activation, control bandwidth&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-07-01&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Daily balancing service accounting&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Accounting of provided balancing energy and related costs (according to balancing service bid document), created on d+1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-07-02&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Monthly balancing service accounting and remuneration report&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Monthly sum of Daily balancing service accounting positions, which are used for remuneration of the flexibility provider&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-08-01&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Forecast of flexible capacity and costs&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The forecast of flexible capacity and costs of a DER is generated for the entire upcoming product duration, that is tendered.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-08-02&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Flexibility merit order&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The flexibility merit order sorts the DER’s flexibility forecasts according to their costs (from cheapest to most expensive).&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IE-08-03&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Actual flexibility of DER&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The actual flexibility bandwidth of a DER&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="7-common-terms-and-definitions">7. Common Terms and Definitions&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="8-custom-information-optional">8. Custom Information (optional)&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Key&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Value&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Refers to Section&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Docs: TIGON</title><link>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/tigon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/tigon/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="1-description-of-the-use-case">1. Description of the Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="11-name-of-the-use-case">1.1. Name of the Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>ID&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Area /Domain(s)/Zone(s)&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name of the Use Case&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy system/Distribution,&lt;/td>
&lt;td>TIGON&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="12-version-management">1.2. Version Management&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Version No.&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Date&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name of author(s)&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Changes&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Approval status&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>0.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2021-11-05T00:00:00&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Maria Fotopoulou, Fotis Stergiopoulos, Dimitrios Rakopoulos (CERTH),&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Draft&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="13-scope-and-objectives-of-use-case">1.3. Scope and Objectives of Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Scope&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Construction of an AC/DC hybrid grid for the efficient distribution of power generated by Renewable Energy Sources (RES) which mostly produce DC power.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Objective(s)&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>-Enhancement of the local grid&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>-Efficient incorporation of DC-based RES and storage in a distribution grid&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>-Definition of topology, voltage levels and required equipement for an AC/DC hybrid grid&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>-Construction of novel power converters&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>-Implementation of Energy Management System (EMS) for hybrid grids&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>-Evaluation of the performance of AC/DC hybrid grids in the case of CIEMAT grid.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Related business case(s)&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Relevant to the AC/DC hybrid grid of the CEA demo site (other use case with the same purpose from the same project).&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="14-narrative-of-use-case">1.4. Narrative of Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Short description&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Design, construction and evaluation of an AC/DC hybrid grid in CIEMAT, Spain including a variety of RES and storage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Complete description&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The CIEMAT demo site includes a PV installation, 1-3 wind turbines, two Battery Energy Storage Systems (BESS) and two sorts of loads (AC and DC). Since the majority of these components utilizes DC power, it would be efficient to have an AC/DC hybrid grid. The topology, the required converters, the operation modes, etc. need to be defined and implemented, which is the purpose of TIGON.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="15-key-performance-indicatiors-kpi">1.5. Key Performance Indicatiors (KPI)&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>ID&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Reference to mentioned use case objectives&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>kpi_01&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Self-consumption rate&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The ratio of consumed renewable energy over the sum of all renewable electricity generated on site.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Efficient incorporation of DC-based RES and storage in a distribution grid.,&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="16-use-case-conditions">1.6. Use case conditions&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Assumptions&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>TIGON&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Prerequisites&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>TIGON&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="17-further-information-to-the-use-case-for-classificationmapping">1.7. Further information to the use case for classification/mapping&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Relation to other use cases&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Level of depth&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Prioritisation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>This use case is beneficial for grid development and RES implementation. It is mandatory for TIGON.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Generic, regional or national relation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Generic&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Nature of the use cases&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Technical/system use case&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Further keywords for classification&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Small scale, medium voltage (MV), low voltage (LV)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="18-general-remarks">1.8. General remarks&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>General remarks&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="2-diagrams-of-use-case">2. Diagrams of Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="DC_hybrid_architecture_for_the_CIEMAT_demo_site" alt="AC/DC hybrid architecture for the CIEMAT demo site">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="3-technical-details">3. Technical Details&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="31-actors">3.1. Actors&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Type&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Further information specific to this Use Case&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>CIEMAT&amp;rsquo;s grid operator&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Distribution system operator&lt;/td>
&lt;td>They shall operate the AC/DC hybrid grid of CIEMAT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Theoretical research entities&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Research centres&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Investigation of architectures, requirements, etc. for grid development.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Constructors of power electronics&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Construction companies&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Construction of appropriate DC-based power electronics, including solid state transformers, DC/DC converters, etc.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Developers of software applications&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Software companies&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Developers of energy management systems, dicision support systems, etc.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>CIEMAT&amp;rsquo;s grid&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Grid (including distributed resources, loads, buses, lines, etc.)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Power lines, distributed resources, loads, buses, etc.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="32-references">3.2. References&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>References Type&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Reference&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Status&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Impact on Use Case&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Organistaor / Organisation&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Link&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Review paper&lt;/td>
&lt;td>State of the Art of Low and Medium Voltage Direct Current (DC) Microgrids&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Published&lt;/td>
&lt;td>High&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/en14185595">https://doi.org/10.3390/en14185595&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Deliverable&lt;/td>
&lt;td>TIGON D2.2 Demo site grids boundary conditions, overall requirements and operation modes&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Finalized&lt;/td>
&lt;td>High&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="4-step-by-step-analysis-of-use-case">4. Step by Step Analysis of Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="41-overview-of-scenarios">4.1. Overview of Scenarios&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Primary Actor&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Triggering Event&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Pre-Condition&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Post-Condition&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CIEMAT demo site: A flexible configuration through BESS for DC-based hybrid grids&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Deployment and integration of AC/DC hybrid solutions in CIEMAT demo site&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CIEMAT demo site: A flexible configuration through BESS for DC-based hybrid grids&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Notes&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="42-steps--scenarios">4.2. Steps – Scenarios&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>CIEMAT demo site: A flexible configuration through BESS for DC-based hybrid grids&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Need for research regarding AC/DC hybrid system designs&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Boundary conditions and baseline for TIGON development&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The objective is to define the baseline and key aspects for the correct development and later deployment of the TIGON solutions, including the modelling and characterization of the CIEMAT demo-site as well as the definition of alternative operation modes and ancillary services to be provided to the main grid.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Completion of the previous step, which is the theoretical analysis of the use case&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Development of physical architecture&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The objective is to design and develop novel physical architectures and grid assets to be implemented at TIGON demo-sites for fostering the implementation of DC-based hybrid grid across Europe&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Completion of the previous step, which is the design of the physical architecture&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Software applications for an efficient monitoring, control and management of the grid&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The objective is to develop innovative monitoring, control and management strategies for an optimized operation and performance of hybrid grids based on DC-architectures with the aim of improving the efficiency, resilience and security of TIGON demo-sites.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Completion of all previous steps, which provide the means for the deployment of AC/DC hybrid systems in the CIEMAT demo site&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CIEMAT demo site: A flexible configuration through BESS for DC-based hybrid grids&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The objective is to deploy and integrate TIGON solutions in CIEMAT demo-site, with the aim of demonstrating a smart and flexible management of MV DC-based grids linked to energy storage systems and providing stability yo the LV hybrid grid.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="5-information-exchanged">5. Information Exchanged&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information exchanged ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Information&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirement&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="6-requirements-optional">6. Requirements (optional)&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Category Identifier&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>mRID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Req_ID&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Req_Name&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CIEMAT demo-site&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Identifier&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>mRID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>I-01&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Design of CIEMAT&amp;rsquo;s grid&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Topologies, voltage levels, KPIs, etc.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>IS-1 (Information Security)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>I-02&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Construction of CIEMAT&amp;rsquo;s grid components&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Details on the constructed power converters, their requirements, etc.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>IS-1&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>I-03&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Software of CIEMAT&amp;rsquo;s grid&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Details regarding the proposed operation of the grid&lt;/td>
&lt;td>IS-1&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>I-04&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Operation of CIEMAT&amp;rsquo;s grid&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Operation and evaluation of the constructed AC/DC hybrid grid.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>IS-1&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="7-common-terms-and-definitions">7. Common Terms and Definitions&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="8-custom-information-optional">8. Custom Information (optional)&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Key&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Value&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Refers to Section&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table></description></item></channel></rss>