<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Smart Grid Use Cases – EBALANCE-PLUS</title><link>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/ebalance-plus/</link><description>Recent content in EBALANCE-PLUS on Smart Grid Use Cases</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/ebalance-plus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: UC1</title><link>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/ebalance-plus/uc1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/ebalance-plus/uc1/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="1-description-of-the-use-case">1. Description of the Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="11-name-of-the-use-case">1.1. Name of the Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>ID&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Area /Domain(s)/Zone(s)&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name of the Use Case&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>/ Generation, Transmission, Distribution, DER and Customer Premises / Station, Operation, Enterprise, Market,&lt;/td>
&lt;td>UC1&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="12-version-management">1.2. Version Management&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Version No.&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Date&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name of author(s)&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Changes&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Approval status&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>V0.9&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2021-02-10T00:00:00&lt;/td>
&lt;td>K. Piotrowski,&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Initial version of the document&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="13-scope-and-objectives-of-use-case">1.3. Scope and Objectives of Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Scope&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The scope of this Use Case is to describe the platform as a means to exchange data between the distributed energy management algorithms that are installed and executed on spatially distributed machines within the energy grid – management units. The scope covers the data exchange, but also other procedures needed to be done on the infrastructure management side, like registering stakeholders and their services, registering management units and defining their hierarchy.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Objective(s)&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The objectives of the Use Case are as follows:&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>a) Platform initialization (preparation phase)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>o Registration of a stakeholder&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>o Registration of a Management Unit and identification of its responsible stakeholder&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>o Defining relations between Management Units (hierarchy relations parent-child)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>o Registration of a services that shall run on the behalf of a stakeholder&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>o Defining stakeholder policies to define allowed data access&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>b) Performing a data exchange within the platform (run-time phase)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Related business case(s)&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>All other Use Cases exchange data based on the mechanisms described in this Use Case.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="14-narrative-of-use-case">1.4. Narrative of Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Short description&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This Use Case aims at demonstrating the functionality provided by the hierarchical energy-related communication platform. It abstracts the data exchange from the main energy management algorithms and by that simplifies the implementation of distributed energy management algorithms. The Use Case presents all the steps and procedures related to the platform, needed for its proper configuration and executed during its run-time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Complete description&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Use Case aims at demonstrating the following main steps:
a) Preparing the platform infrastructure
b) Performing data exchange between distributed processes (services) executed on distributed management units (MUs)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These two steps can be further split into procedures that need to be applied to achieve the goal of the step, but these procedures can be applied in different combinations and sequences, depending on the given deployment. But in any case the infrastructure needs to be prepared first, before the data exchange can take place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A deployment starts with the top level units (ebplus discovery and authority). These units are responsible for the organizational procedures related to the platform, like registration, certification, revocation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, each stakeholder needs to be registered in the system. A stakeholder is any actor that participates in the energy grid, being either a customer or (any service) provider. A stakeholder is relevant for the platform if there is data acquired or generated by that stakeholder or related to that stakeholder. After being registered the stakeholder obtains a unique identity in the system that she can prove to others with a certificate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to create the physical infrastructure for the platform it is necessary to install the management units (hardware and software) and to register each of them within the platform. Here, similar to the stakeholder registration, each management unit obtains a unique identity and a certificate to prove the identity to others. The management unit is additionally linked to a specific stakeholder that is in charge of the management unit and has physical access to it. This stakeholder and management unit relation can be, for instance, defined by the premises the unit is installed within. After a management unit is registered in the system, it can be attached to the existing topology of units by defining its place in the hierarchy within the platform. This definition is done by creating a parent-child link between two management units. This relation is 1 to n, meaning that one parent can have many children, but one child can have only one parent (at a time). To define this link, it is necessary to configure both the management units properly, i.e., the child is added to the children configuration set on the parent MU and the parent is added to the parent (one element) configuration set on the child MU. This setting is local to this two MUs, it is not forced or configured by the top units, as it can be dynamic if the deployment allows topology/hierarchy changes, for instance, to improve the reliability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to create data sources and exchange points it is necessary to register services that use the platform. A service is an implementation that accesses the data in the platform and executes a local algorithm processing the data and triggering actions or generating new data. These local services cooperate and together they implement a distributed algorithm. The locally installed piece of software (service) is executed on a management unit on behalf of a given stakeholder. It means that the same piece of software may be executed on the same management unit but for different stakeholders. By that we have two different instances of the algorithm, but performing their tasks for different stakeholders. Thus, within the platform not the piece of software – service is registered, but its specific instance to be run by a specific stakeholder. Such registered services to be run by specific stakeholders also get their certificates to prove their identity. This approach allows to specify data access policy that allows restricting the data accesses for specific algorithms by specific stakeholders only.
Data stored by a service onto the platform is labeled as data belonging to the stakeholder the service runs on behalf of. By default each service run for a given stakeholder can access the data by that stakeholder without restrictions. But in order to access data of other stakeholders it is necessary that a proper access control policy is defined. Such policy specifies the allowed access patterns for given stakeholder/service configurations. And as the data access policy is handled by the MU where the data was written by a service of a stakeholder, it is also necessary to define the policy at that management unit. The best way to do that is to set it up while the service first starts. The access policy is then available on other MUs in the platform as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, the data exchange between the running services may happen. The data exchange ways include reading, writing data, but reading can also be extended to subscribing to specific events, resulting in periodic data delivery or delivery of each newly available value. To exploit the hierarchical feature of the energy grid it is advised to perform data exchange according to the parent-children hierarchy, but indeed any other data exchange is possible as well. It is only necessary to know the identity of the target management unit, where the desired data origins from. Additionally, it is of course also necessary to have the right to access the desired data (policy definition by the data owner).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="15-key-performance-indicatiors-kpi">1.5. Key Performance Indicatiors (KPI)&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>ID&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Reference to mentioned use case objectives&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>KPI.1.01&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Platform reliability&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Each data exchange request shall be accomplished with a clear outcome. Each condition in the platform has a defined influence on the data exchange result. Analysis of the platform state under the existence of data exchange requests gives a metric of the system reliability.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Objective b),&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="16-use-case-conditions">1.6. Use case conditions&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Assumptions&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>UC1&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Prerequisites&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>UC1&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="17-further-information-to-the-use-case-for-classificationmapping">1.7. Further information to the use case for classification/mapping&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Relation to other use cases&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Level of depth&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Prioritisation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Obligatory&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Generic, regional or national relation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Generic&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Nature of the use cases&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Technical&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Further keywords for classification&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Information Management System&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="18-general-remarks">1.8. General remarks&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>General remarks&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="2-diagrams-of-use-case">2. Diagrams of Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="Component_layer.png" alt="SGAM - Component Layer">
&lt;img src="Communication_layer.png" alt="SGAM - Communication Layer">
&lt;img src="Information_layer.png" alt="SGAM -Information layer">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="3-technical-details">3. Technical Details&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="31-actors">3.1. Actors&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Type&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Further information specific to this Use Case&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Data source&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Any service by any stakeholder&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Any service by any stakeholder storing data in the platform&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Data sink&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Any service by any stakeholder&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Any service by any stakeholder reading data in the platform&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="32-references">3.2. References&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>References Type&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Reference&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Status&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Impact on Use Case&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Organistaor / Organisation&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Link&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="4-step-by-step-analysis-of-use-case">4. Step by Step Analysis of Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="41-overview-of-scenarios">4.1. Overview of Scenarios&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Primary Actor&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Triggering Event&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Pre-Condition&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Post-Condition&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>PS1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Storing data&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Data source stores data in the platform&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Storing data&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>PS2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Reading data&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Data sink requests and obtains the data from the platform&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Reading data&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Notes&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="42-steps--scenarios">4.2. Steps – Scenarios&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Storing data&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Data source issues a store request&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Data source issues a store request. The data source is identified by the platform.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Platform stores the data and replies with a reply.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>After successful processing of the request the data is stored in the platform.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Reading data&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Data sink issues a data read request&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The data sink issues a request to read the data. The request may be either a single reading or a subscription for a series. The platform identifies the data sink and verifies if the data sink can access the requested data.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Data sink&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Platform issues a reply for the request&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>After successful processing of the request the platform replies with data. This can be a single reply or a series of reply messages.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Data sink&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="5-information-exchanged">5. Information Exchanged&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information exchanged ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Information&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirement&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="6-requirements-optional">6. Requirements (optional)&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Category Identifier&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>mRID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Req_ID&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Req_Name&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&amp;lsquo;Ebalance-plus Hierarchical Energy Communication Platform&amp;rsquo;&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Identifier&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>mRID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>EB.WR&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Store request&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Store request, containing the data to be stored together with meta description of the data and the identity of the data source (the requester).&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EB.WR&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>EB.WRR&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Store reply&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Store reply, containing the result of the request processing.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EB.WRR&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>EB.RD&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Read request&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Read request, containing the meta description of the requested data and the identity of the data sink (the requester).&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EB.RD&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>EB.RDR&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Read reply&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Read reply, containing the result of the request processing and the requested data (if the access was granted)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EB.RDR&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="7-common-terms-and-definitions">7. Common Terms and Definitions&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="8-custom-information-optional">8. Custom Information (optional)&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Key&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Value&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Refers to Section&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Docs: UC10</title><link>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/ebalance-plus/uc10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/ebalance-plus/uc10/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="1-description-of-the-use-case">1. Description of the Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="11-name-of-the-use-case">1.1. Name of the Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>ID&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Area /Domain(s)/Zone(s)&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name of the Use Case&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>/ Customer premises / Process, Field, Station, Operation, Enterprises, Market,&lt;/td>
&lt;td>UC10&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="12-version-management">1.2. Version Management&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Version No.&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Date&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name of author(s)&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Changes&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Approval status&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>V1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2020-09-25T00:00:00&lt;/td>
&lt;td>DTU,&lt;/td>
&lt;td>First Draft&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="13-scope-and-objectives-of-use-case">1.3. Scope and Objectives of Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Scope&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This use case is aimed at unlocking the energy flexibility potential of end-users using smart energy management system, i.e. price-based or CO2-based optimal control, to enabling their participation in demand-response programs.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Objective(s)&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>1. Reduce building energy bills and CO2 emissions&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2. Enable an automatic load response to price signals (price-based demand response programs)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3. Enhance the control strategy of power-to-heat technologies coupled with thermal storage to increase building flexibility&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4. Develop forecasting algorithms to better exploit building flexibility&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Related business case(s)&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Associate with UC7&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="14-narrative-of-use-case">1.4. Narrative of Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Short description&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Price/CO2-based control is an indirect control mechanism that can be used to drive end-users’ power consumption on the basis of signals representative of market or grid (e.g., TSO/DSO) requirements. Indeed, end-users linked to time-varying electricity or network tariffs and equipped with smart controllers can react to changes in the price of electricity over time by shifting their consumption from peak to low-tariff hours, thus reducing their energy costs on the one hand and the overall demand, during peak-hours, on the other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Complete description&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Demand response (DR) is a promising way to exploit end users’ flexibility for supporting grid balancing and management. Among DR programs, price-based programs (also known as implicit DR programs) are recognized as the most suited for engaging low-voltage end-users, like households, in grid operations. Indeed, utilities equipped with controllers capable to react to external signals, like time-varying electricity prices, can exploit storage capacities (e.g.e.g., water of swimming pools) to implement load-shifting strategies that, on the one hand, reduce their energy cost and, on the other end, provide a service to the grid (e.g., peak-shaving, congestion relief, etc.). The present use case is structured as follows:
(1) Each day, the market operators upload the market clearing prices (spot prices) for the next 24 hours to the Cloud platform, where they will be accessible to all the authorized end-users.
(2) X hours before Real-Time Operations (RTO), the Control Management Unit (CMU) acquires the electricity tariffs from a Cloud platform (Internet service), and previously to RTO the CMU acquires all the information (e.g., sensors data, weather forecasting, etc.) needed to optimize the end-user energy consumption over the considered control horizon (e.g. 24 hours).&lt;br>
(3) The CMU optimize the end-user’s consumption on the basis of the data gathered and implement the optimal control action.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="15-key-performance-indicatiors-kpi">1.5. Key Performance Indicatiors (KPI)&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>ID&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Reference to mentioned use case objectives&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>KPI_1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Operational cost-saving (%)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy cost reduction by participating in price-based demand response programs (e.g., €/day)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>1,&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="16-use-case-conditions">1.6. Use case conditions&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Assumptions&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>UC10&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Prerequisites&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>UC10&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="17-further-information-to-the-use-case-for-classificationmapping">1.7. Further information to the use case for classification/mapping&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Relation to other use cases&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Level of depth&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Prioritisation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Mandatory&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Generic, regional or national relation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Generic&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Nature of the use cases&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Technical&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Further keywords for classification&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Demand Response, Distribution Network Operation, Aggregator, Energy Flexibility&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="18-general-remarks">1.8. General remarks&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>General remarks&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="2-diagrams-of-use-case">2. Diagrams of Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="UC10-Diagram.png" alt="Overview of the use case">
&lt;img src="Component_layer.png" alt="SGAM - Component Layer">
&lt;img src="Function_layer.png" alt="SGAM - Function Layer">
&lt;img src="Communication_layer.png" alt="SGAM - Communication Layer">
&lt;img src="Information_layer.png" alt="SGAM - Information Layer">
&lt;img src="Buisness_layer.png" alt="SGAM - Buisness Layer">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="3-technical-details">3. Technical Details&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="31-actors">3.1. Actors&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Type&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Further information specific to this Use Case&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Sensors, Smart meters&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Gather data at building level (e.g. indoor temperature and humidity, HP power consumption, water pool temperature) and broadcast them to the Control Management Unit through the IoT Gateway.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Controllable loads&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Controllable devices within a building, which consume electricity, such as heat pumps, electric boilers, ventilation systems, dishwashers, fridges, freezers, dryers etc.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>IoT gateway&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>IoT Gateway to integrate multi-vendor devices with processing capability (embedded Raspberry-Pi).&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Cloud Platform&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>A cloud and web-based software platform which provides data-driven energy performance reporting, alarm, and notification system, compatible with all devices and systems such as smart meters, energy analyzers, automation systems and 3rd party software​, providing an intuitive user interface for building and district level stakeholders.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Customer Management Unit (CMU)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Application that optimize the operation of the controllable loads on the basis of price/CO2 forecasts.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Load controller&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Unit deployed at building level to control IoT devices and loads (e.g. Heat Pump).&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="32-references">3.2. References&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>References Type&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Reference&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Status&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Impact on Use Case&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Organistaor / Organisation&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Link&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="4-step-by-step-analysis-of-use-case">4. Step by Step Analysis of Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="41-overview-of-scenarios">4.1. Overview of Scenarios&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Primary Actor&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Triggering Event&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Pre-Condition&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Post-Condition&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>PS1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy cost/CO2 optimization&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The energy balancing/flexibility platform sends to every CMU/IoT gateway prices and forecasting and they perform the CO2/Cost optimization.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy cost/CO2 optimization&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>AS1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>End users preference prioritization&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The CMU selects a non-optimal operation given the users preferences.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>End users preference prioritization&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Notes&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="42-steps--scenarios">4.2. Steps – Scenarios&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Energy cost/CO2 optimization&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>11-15 min&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Sensors and Smart meters broadcast data to the IoT gateway.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>hourly&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The Cloud Platform acquires market data (e.g. energy prices, CO2), complement it with additional information (e.g. weather forecasting, booking status of summer houses), and make them available to the CMU.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>hourly&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>IoT gateway gathers data from the Cloud.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>hourly&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>IoT gateway transmits data gathered to the Control Management Unit.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>5&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Data (prices, weather forecasting, booking status) acquired&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The Customer Management Unit defines the optimal control strategy to unlock the energy flexibility potential of the end users.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>6&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Optimization problem solved&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The Control Management Unit broadcasts the optimal control signals (i.e. setpoints) to the Load Controller.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>7&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Optimal setpoints received&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The load controller reformats the setpoints, or operating status, of the controllable devices, and broadcasts the new values to the controlled loads.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>8&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Optimal setpoints received&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Controllable devices update their operation parameters according to the new optimal setpoints.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>End users preference prioritization&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Customer setpoints received&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The customers reformat the setpoints of the controllable devices&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Customer setpoints received&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Controllable devices update their operation parameters according to the new setpoints.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="5-information-exchanged">5. Information Exchanged&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information exchanged ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Information&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirement&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="6-requirements-optional">6. Requirements (optional)&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Category Identifier&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>mRID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Req_ID&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Req_Name&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&amp;lsquo;Price/CO2 based optimization&amp;rsquo;&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Identifier&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>mRID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Sensor and Smart meter measurements&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Air temperature and humidity, pool water temperature, electric consumption.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Privacy&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Price/ CO2 data&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Market data: electricity prices and CO2 emission factor&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Weather forecast&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Weather forecasting&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Availability of data&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Convenience&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Additional parameters that affect the optimal control problem (i.e., occupants’ comfort requirements).&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Availability of data&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>5&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Optimal control strategy&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Outputs of the optimal control problem solved to unlock the energy flexibility potential of end users.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>5&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>6&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Optimal setpoints&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Steering signals used to control/modify the operational status of the controllable devices.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>6&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>7&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Operation parameters&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Parameters identifying the operational status of the controlled devices (e.g., on/off)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>7&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="7-common-terms-and-definitions">7. Common Terms and Definitions&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="8-custom-information-optional">8. Custom Information (optional)&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Key&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Value&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Refers to Section&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Docs: UC5</title><link>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/ebalance-plus/uc5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/ebalance-plus/uc5/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="1-description-of-the-use-case">1. Description of the Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="11-name-of-the-use-case">1.1. Name of the Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>ID&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Area /Domain(s)/Zone(s)&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name of the Use Case&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Distribution DER / Field, Station, Operation,&lt;/td>
&lt;td>UC5&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="12-version-management">1.2. Version Management&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Version No.&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Date&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name of author(s)&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Changes&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Approval status&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>0.9&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2020-11-25T00:00:00&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Nikolaos Livanos, Vaggelis Alifragkis, Georgios Stravopodis,&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="13-scope-and-objectives-of-use-case">1.3. Scope and Objectives of Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Scope&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The scope of the proposed Use Case is to implement Volt-VAr optimization approaches in the context of the eBalance+ project, by means of intelligent management units and optimization algorithms in the application field (i.e. Distribution Substations, RES, etc.).&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Objective(s)&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>a. To demonstrate the impact of Volt/VAr optimization on voltage stability&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>b. To demonstrate the impact of Volt/VAr optimization on technical power losses&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>c. To demonstrate the impact of Volt/VAr optimization on RES curtailment&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>d. To demonstrate the performance of Volt/VAr optimization both with a centralized and a distributed implementation with respect to possible failures in both approaches.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Related business case(s)&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="14-narrative-of-use-case">1.4. Narrative of Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Short description&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The proposed Use Case refers to Volt-VAr optimization in a Power Distribution Grid incorporating DER (mainly RES), aiming to apply and demonstrate concepts and technologies of the eBalance+ project. The Use Case shall evaluate a specific distribution grid topology (TBD) in three different setups: 1. Laboratory Numerical Simulation, 2. Laboratory Simulation with Hardware-in-the-Loop (of eBalance+ management units), 3. Actual performance in project’s demo site(s). Regarding setup 3 (demo site) certain modifications in the distribution grid topology are anticipated, mainly due to the limitations of access to grid assets, as well as the limitations to intervene in the present control schemes. Two core scenarios will be presented: 1. Centralized, 2. Distributed. In the Centralized Scenario the Volt-VAr control is arbitrated and executed in the (A)DMS system (assumed to exist). The information is exchanged via the eBalance+ middleware and the MVGMU, LVGMU and DERMU devices (management units) are mainly used for communication interfacing and as remote terminal points (RTUs). In the Distributed scenario, the Volt-Var control is performed in the MVGMU device as an alternate scenario in case of central systems failures. As in the Centralized scenario, the LVGMU and DERMU are used for communication interfacing, again following eBalance+ middleware information routes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Complete description&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The present Use Case aims on the following:
• Increased RES penetration in power distribution grids causes congestion and effective Volt-VAr optimization can intelligently manage RES to alleviate the problem.
• An information/communication middleware (ebalance+) adopted by intelligent management units installed in the Operation, Station, and Field domains (following SGAM notation) can increase overall system resilience by means of automatic re-configuration and continuity of Volt-VAr service.
• Intelligent management units in the Station and Field domains (e.g. MVGMU) are able to provide optimized Volt-VAr service.
• Distributed intelligence could support Volt-VAr optimization approaches
• Simulate respective Volt-Var optimization approaches
• Apply Hardware-in-the-loop of the eBalance+ intelligent devices in the above simulations
• Apply selected Volt-VAr optimization scenarios in the eBalance+ pilot installations
• Measure and analyze performance in the demo sites&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Volt-VAr Use Case is based on the following methodology:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Define a configurable power distribution grid topology
a. Based on detailed analysis the topology may incorporate assets, such as: HV/MV Substation, Substation Capacitor Bank, Substation Transformer with On-Load TAP changer, MV RES, MV/LV Transformer with Voltage Regulator, MV Line Capacitors, LV RES, MV Loads, LV Loads, etc.
b. The topology shall define the connections between the assets and perhaps possible reconfigurations (e.g. power switches, etc.)
c. The RES generation shall be configurable (e.g. define three RES penetration scenarios: 50%, 100%, 200%).
d. Part of the overall topology will be similar to the demo installation topologies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Define various congestion situations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Define specific optimization objective functions: Voltage Range, Power Loss Reduction, Minimum RES Curtailment&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Define specific KPIs to support evaluation, comparisons and reporting: Voltage Violations (Frequency, Duration, Number, Excess), Power Losses, RES Energy, (optional KPIs depending on available control of assets: number of capacitor transitions, number of OLTC transitions, etc.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implement two scenarios:
a. Centralized Volt-VAr: the solver is executed in the (A)DMS at the DSO’s Operation Center
b. Distributed Volt-VAr: the solver is executed in the intelligent device in the Primary Distribution Substation (e.g. MVGMU)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Evaluate and compare the two scenarios&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Evaluate and compare the grid’s performance before and after the application of optimization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Use Case shall be implemented according to the following phases:
a. Phase 1: Analysis, definitions and laboratory numerical simulations
b. Phase 2: Laboratory simulations with Hardware-in-the-loop (e.g. MVGMU, LVGMU, DERMU in the simulation loop)
c. Phase 3: Demo sites operations&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="15-key-performance-indicatiors-kpi">1.5. Key Performance Indicatiors (KPI)&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>ID&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Reference to mentioned use case objectives&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>KPI.01&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Reduction of voltage violations&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Based on the application of the Voltage Range objective function, this KPI measures the Frequency, Count and Duration of Voltage Violations per bus&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Voltage Range,&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="16-use-case-conditions">1.6. Use case conditions&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Assumptions&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>UC5&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Prerequisites&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="17-further-information-to-the-use-case-for-classificationmapping">1.7. Further information to the use case for classification/mapping&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Relation to other use cases&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Level of depth&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Prioritisation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Mandatory&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Generic, regional or national relation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Generic&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Nature of the use cases&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Technical&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Further keywords for classification&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Advanced Distribution Management System, optimisation, simulation, RES, substation&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="18-general-remarks">1.8. General remarks&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>General remarks&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="2-diagrams-of-use-case">2. Diagrams of Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="Sequence_Diagram-Sc1-part1.png" alt="Sequence Diagram - Scenario 1 part 1/2">
&lt;img src="Sequence_Diagram-Sc1-part2.png" alt="Sequence Diagram - Scenario 1 part 2/2">
&lt;img src="Sequence_Diagram-Sc2.png" alt="Sequence Diagram - Scenario 2">
&lt;img src="Component_layer_scenario1.png" alt="SGAM - Component Layer - Scenario 1">
&lt;img src="Component_layer_scenario2.png" alt="SGAM - Component Layer - Scenario 2">
&lt;img src="Function_layer_scenario1.png" alt="SGAM - Function Layer - Scenario 1">
&lt;img src="Function_layer_scenario2.png" alt="SGAM - Function Layer - Scenario 2">
&lt;img src="Communication_layer_scenario1.png" alt="SGAM - Communication Layer - Scenario 1">
&lt;img src="Communication_layer_scenario2.png" alt="SGAM - Communication Layer - Scenario 2">
&lt;img src="Information_layer_scenario1.png" alt="SGAM - Information Layer - Scenario 1">
&lt;img src="Information_layer_scenario2.png" alt="SGAM - Information Layer - Scenario 2">
&lt;img src="Buisness_layer.png" alt="SGAM - Buisness Layer">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="3-technical-details">3. Technical Details&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="31-actors">3.1. Actors&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Type&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Further information specific to this Use Case&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>DSO / Utility&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Role&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Responsible for operating, ensuring the maintenance of and, if necessary, developing the distribution system in a given area&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Service Provider&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Role&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Industrial partner involved in the ebalance+ project providing providing management units and algorithms&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>DER Owner&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Role&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The owner of DER installation (see below) or the appointed representative that allows flexibility management&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>DER installation(s)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System(s)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Small generation plant(s) (mainly of renewable energy) owned by a legal person&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>MVGMU, LVGMU, DERMU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System(s)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>All devices placed on MV/LV network for monitoring or gathering information on grid&amp;rsquo;s situation or electrical parameters values. It also includes the IS associated&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>SCADA, (A)DMS&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Systems&lt;/td>
&lt;td>All the hardware and software associated, used at power command to control and monitor the network&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>DMS.VVC&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The software that performs the algorithms and produces the desired results. Operates at the DMS level&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>MVGMU.VVC&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The software that performs the algorithms and produces the desired results. Operates at the MVGMU level&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="32-references">3.2. References&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>References Type&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Reference&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Status&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Impact on Use Case&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Organistaor / Organisation&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Link&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="4-step-by-step-analysis-of-use-case">4. Step by Step Analysis of Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="41-overview-of-scenarios">4.1. Overview of Scenarios&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Primary Actor&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Triggering Event&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Pre-Condition&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Post-Condition&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>PS1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Centralized Volt/Var Optimization with RES Variability&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The optimization logic is performed on the Distribution Management System level by collecting readings from the complete underlying grid. In turn control actions computed by the algorithm are distributed to the complete grid. The Primary scenario is separated in the following cases: 1. Nominal scenario, where the grid experiences no failures 2. DMS failure 3. MVGMU failure 4. LVGMU failure 5. DERMU failure&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Centralized Volt/Var Optimization with RES Variability&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>AS1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Distributed Volt/Var Optimization with RES Variability&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The optimization logic is performed on the Medium Voltage Grid level by collecting readings from the complete underlying grid. In turn control actions computed by the algorithm are distributed to the complete grid&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Distributed Volt/Var Optimization with RES Variability&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Notes&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="42-steps--scenarios">4.2. Steps – Scenarios&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Centralized Volt/Var Optimization with RES Variability&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Periodic Execution /No Failures – Set Inputs&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>DMS sets all the required input to VVC&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Periodic Execution – Optimization&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>VVC performs optimization algorithm on given inputs (Optimum Power flow)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EXECUTE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1.3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Periodic Execution – Get Outputs&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>VVC sends control signals based on results&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CHANGE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>[VVC.008] The VVC function shall calculate the following:&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Capacitor Bank New Status (on/off per capacitor)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TAP Position (number)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Line Capacitor Status (on/off flag)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RES Set-Point (desired power factor per RES source)
[VVC.009] All outputs shall be provided to the SCADA in the case of DMS deployment
[VVC.010] All outputs shall be provided to the MVGMU.RTU in the case of MVGMU deployment
[VVC.011] Any not-set values shall be denoted by “null” |
| 1.4 | Reporting | None | VVC computes and reports KPI compliance (continued process across multiple runs) | REPORT | | | | [VVC.012] The VVC shall be able to report the value of its KPIs
[VVC.013] The KPIs shall be measured by the VVC function after it provides outputs. |
| 2.1 | DMS Failure Set Inputs | None | DMS.VVC tries to collect inputs but communication has failed. (Please see AS1) | GET | | | | |
| 3.1 | MVGMU Failure Set Input | None | DMS.VVC tries to collect all inputs but MVGMU fails to provide | GET | | | | |
| 3.2 | Periodic Execution – Optimization | None | VVC performs optimization algorithm on given inputs (Optimum Power flow) without input from MVGMU | EXECUTE | | | | |
| 3.3 | Periodic Execution – Get Outputs | None | VVC sends control signals based on results | CHANGE | | | | [VVC.008] The VVC function shall calculate the following:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capacitor Bank New Status (on/off per capacitor)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TAP Position (number)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Line Capacitor Status (on/off flag)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RES Set-Point (desired power factor per RES source)
[VVC.009] All outputs shall be provided to the SCADA in the case of DMS deployment
[VVC.010] All outputs shall be provided to the MVGMU.RTU in the case of MVGMU deployment
[VVC.011] Any not-set values shall be denoted by “null” |
| 3.4 | Reporting | None | VVC computes and reports KPI compliance (continued process across multiple runs) | REPORT | | | | [VVC.012] The VVC shall be able to report the value of its KPIs
[VVC.013] The KPIs shall be measured by the VVC function after it provides outputs. |
| 4.1 | LVGMU Failure Set Input | None | DMS.VVC tries to collect all inputs but LVGMU fails to provide | GET | | | | |
| 4.2 | Periodic Execution – Optimization | None | VVC performs optimization algorithm on given inputs (Optimum Power flow) without input from LVGMU | EXECUTE | | | | |
| 4.3 | Periodic Execution – Get Outputs | None | VVC sends control signals based on results | CHANGE | | | | [VVC.008] The VVC function shall calculate the following:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capacitor Bank New Status (on/off per capacitor)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TAP Position (number)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Line Capacitor Status (on/off flag)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RES Set-Point (desired power factor per RES source)
[VVC.009] All outputs shall be provided to the SCADA in the case of DMS deployment
[VVC.010] All outputs shall be provided to the MVGMU.RTU in the case of MVGMU deployment
[VVC.011] Any not-set values shall be denoted by “null” |
| 4.4 | Reporting | None | VVC computes and reports KPI compliance (continued process across multiple runs) | REPORT | | | | [VVC.012] The VVC shall be able to report the value of its KPIs
[VVC.013] The KPIs shall be measured by the VVC function after it provides outputs. |
| 5.1 | DERMU Failure Set Input | None | DMS.VVC tries to collect all inputs but DERMU fails to provide | GET | | | | |
| 5.2 | Periodic Execution – Optimization | None | VVC performs optimization algorithm on given inputs (Optimum Power flow) without input from DERMU | CHANGE | | | | |
| 5.3 | Periodic Execution – Get Outputs | None | VVC sends control signals based on results | CHANGE | | | | [VVC.008] The VVC function shall calculate the following:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capacitor Bank New Status (on/off per capacitor)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TAP Position (number)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Line Capacitor Status (on/off flag)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RES Set-Point (desired power factor per RES source)
[VVC.009] All outputs shall be provided to the SCADA in the case of DMS deployment
[VVC.010] All outputs shall be provided to the MVGMU.RTU in the case of MVGMU deployment
[VVC.011] Any not-set values shall be denoted by “null” |
| 5.4 | Reporting | None | VVC computes and reports KPI compliance (continued process across multiple runs) | REPORT | | | | [VVC.012] The VVC shall be able to report the value of its KPIs
[VVC.013] The KPIs shall be measured by the VVC function after it provides outputs. |&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Distributed Volt/Var Optimization with RES Variability&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>0&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Configuration&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>MVGMU Configures VVC according to VVC.CONF&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>[VVC.001] The execution period shall be expressed in seconds&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>[VVC.002] The topology provided to the VVC function shall include the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Line Specification (length, conductance)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Load Specification&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Generator Specification (rated power)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RES Generator Specification (rater power, inverter specification)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Transformer Specification (voltage step, losses)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capacitor specification (capacitance)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TAP Specification (voltage Step) |
| 1.1 | Periodic Execution /No Failures – Set Inputs | None | MVGMU sets all the required input to VVC | GET | | | | |
| 1.2 | Periodic Execution – Optimization | None | VVC performs optimization algorithm on given inputs (Optimum Power flow) | EXECUTE | | | | |
| 1.3 | Periodic Execution – Get Outputs | None | VVC sends control signals based on results | CHANGE | | | | [VVC.008] The VVC function shall calculate the following:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capacitor Bank New Status (on/off per capacitor)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TAP Position (number)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Line Capacitor Status (on/off flag)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RES Set-Point (desired power factor per RES source)
[VVC.009] All outputs shall be provided to the SCADA in the case of DMS deployment
[VVC.010] All outputs shall be provided to the MVGMU.RTU in the case of MVGMU deployment
[VVC.011] Any not-set values shall be denoted by “null” |
| 1.4 | Reporting | None | VVC computes and reports KPI compliance (continued process across multiple runs) | REPORT | | | | [VVC.012] The VVC shall be able to report the value of its KPIs
[VVC.013] The KPIs shall be measured by the VVC function after it provides outputs. |
| 2.1 | DMS Failure Set Inputs | None | MVGMU.VVC tries to collect inputs but DMS has failed | GET | | | | |
| 2.2 | Periodic Execution – Optimization | None | VVC performs optimization algorithm on given inputs (Optimum Power flow) without input from MVGMU | EXECUTE | | | | |
| 2.3 | Periodic Execution – Get Outputs | None | VVC sends control signals based on results | CHANGE | | | | [VVC.008] The VVC function shall calculate the following:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capacitor Bank New Status (on/off per capacitor)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TAP Position (number)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Line Capacitor Status (on/off flag)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RES Set-Point (desired power factor per RES source)
[VVC.009] All outputs shall be provided to the SCADA in the case of DMS deployment
[VVC.010] All outputs shall be provided to the MVGMU.RTU in the case of MVGMU deployment
[VVC.011] Any not-set values shall be denoted by “null” |
| 2.4 | Reporting | None | VVC computes and reports KPI compliance (continued process across multiple runs) | REPORT | | | | [VVC.012] The VVC shall be able to report the value of its KPIs
[VVC.013] The KPIs shall be measured by the VVC function after it provides outputs. |
| 3.1 | MVGMU Failure Set Input | None | MVGMU.VVC tries to collect all inputs but MVGMU fails to provide | GET | | | | |
| 4.1 | LVGMU Failure Set Input | None | MVGMU.VVC tries to collect all inputs but LVGMU fails to provide | GET | | | | |
| 4.2 | Periodic Execution – Optimization | None | VVC performs optimization algorithm on given inputs (Optimum Power flow) without input from LVGMU | EXECUTE | | | | |
| 4.3 | Periodic Execution – Get Outputs | None | VVC sends control signals based on results | CHANGE | | | | [VVC.008] The VVC function shall calculate the following:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capacitor Bank New Status (on/off per capacitor)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TAP Position (number)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Line Capacitor Status (on/off flag)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RES Set-Point (desired power factor per RES source)
[VVC.009] All outputs shall be provided to the SCADA in the case of DMS deployment
[VVC.010] All outputs shall be provided to the MVGMU.RTU in the case of MVGMU deployment
[VVC.011] Any not-set values shall be denoted by “null” |
| 4.4 | Reporting | None | VVC computes and reports KPI compliance (continued process across multiple runs) | REPORT | | | | [VVC.012] The VVC shall be able to report the value of its KPIs
[VVC.013] The KPIs shall be measured by the VVC function after it provides outputs. |
| 5.1 | DERMU Failure Set Input | None | MVGMU.VVC tries to collect all inputs but DERMU fails to provide | GET | | | | |
| 5.2 | Periodic Execution – Optimization | None | VVC performs optimization algorithm on given inputs (Optimum Power flow) without input from DERMU | CHANGE | | | | |
| 5.3 | Periodic Execution – Get Outputs | None | VVC sends control signals based on results | CHANGE | | | | [VVC.008] The VVC function shall calculate the following:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capacitor Bank New Status (on/off per capacitor)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TAP Position (number)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Line Capacitor Status (on/off flag)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RES Set-Point (desired power factor per RES source)
[VVC.009] All outputs shall be provided to the SCADA in the case of DMS deployment
[VVC.010] All outputs shall be provided to the MVGMU.RTU in the case of MVGMU deployment
[VVC.011] Any not-set values shall be denoted by “null” |
| 5.4 | Reporting | None | VVC computes and reports KPI compliance (continued process across multiple runs) | REPORT | | | | [VVC.012] The VVC shall be able to report the value of its KPIs
[VVC.013] The KPIs shall be measured by the VVC function after it provides outputs. |&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h1 id="5-information-exchanged">5. Information Exchanged&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information exchanged ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Information&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirement&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="6-requirements-optional">6. Requirements (optional)&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Category Identifier&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>mRID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Req_ID&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Req_Name&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&amp;lsquo;Volt-VAr optimization with increasing RES generation&amp;rsquo;&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Identifier&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>mRID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>VVC.CONF&lt;/td>
&lt;td>VVC Configuration&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Describes all the configuration options needed to be set to the VVC from the SCADA or RTU system that contains the VVC. These options only need to be set once and are:&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Grid Topology&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Execution Period | [VVC.001] The execution period shall be expressed in seconds&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>[VVC.002] The topology provided to the VVC function shall include the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Line Specification (length, conductance)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Load Specification&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Generator Specification (rated power)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RES Generator Specification (rater power, inverter specification)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Transformer Specification (voltage step, losses)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capacitor specification (capacitance)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TAP Specification (voltage Step) |
| VVC.IN | VVC Input Execution Parameters | Describes the Information needed for a Volt/Var execution loop to compute. These are provided by the SCADA or RTU system that contains the VVC and are the following:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Voltage (Distribution Grid)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Active Power (Distribution Grid)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reactive Power (Distribution Grid)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TAP Position&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capacitor Bank Status&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Voltage (RES)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Active Power (RES)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reactive Power (RES) | [VVC.003] The VVC function shall get as input the Distribution Grid state, which is:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Voltage (V)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Active Power (MW)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reactive Power (MW)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TAP Position (number)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capacitor Bank Status (on/off per capacitor)
[VVC.004] The VVC function shall get as input the RES state, which is:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Voltage (V)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Active Power (MW)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reactive Power (MVar)
[VVC.005] All the inputs shall be provided by the SCADA in the case of DMS deployment (scenario 1)
[VVC.006] All the inputs shall be provided by the MVGMU RTU in the case of MVGMU deployment (scenario 2)
[VVC.007] All the inputs shall be provided
Inputs that have no value for any reason shall be denoted as “null” |
| VVC.OUT | VVC Output Results | Describes the results returned from the VVC after an execution loop. All results are returned to the SCADA or RTU system that contains the VVC which is then responsible to route them to the correct components. The output variables are:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capacitor Bank New Status&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TAP Position&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Line Capacitor Status&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RES set-points | [VVC.008] The VVC function shall calculate the following:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capacitor Bank New Status (on/off per capacitor)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TAP Position (number)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Line Capacitor Status (on/off flag)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RES Set-Point (desired power factor per RES source)
[VVC.009] All outputs shall be provided to the SCADA in the case of DMS deployment
[VVC.010] All outputs shall be provided to the MVGMU.RTU in the case of MVGMU deployment
[VVC.011] Any not-set values shall be denoted by “null” |
| VVC.RPT | VVC Reporting | Describes the metrics computed after operation for the evaluation target KPIs. These metrics are aggregated in a temporal and a statistical manner and are persistent across runs. The Metrics are:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Voltage Violations Frequency&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Voltage Violations Count&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Voltage Violation Duration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Voltage Violation Excess&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Power Losses&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RES Energy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RES Curtailment percentage&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of Capacitor Switches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of OLTC Switches | [VVC.012] The VVC shall be able to report the value of its KPIs
[VVC.013] The KPIs shall be measured by the VVC function after it provides outputs. |
| MGVMU.OUT | MGVMU RTU Outputs/Measurements | Describes all the values measured and retrieved from the specific RTU. These are:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capacitor Bank Measurement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tap Measurement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Voltage&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reactive Power&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Active Power | [VVC.014] The MVGMU.RTU shall provide its measurements to the SCADA (scenario 1)
[VVC.015] The MVGMU shall provide its measurements to the VVC function directly (scenario 2)
[VVC.016] The measurements of the MVGMU.RTU shall be:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capacitor Bank Status (on/off per capacitor)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tap Measurement (number)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Voltage (V)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reactive Power (MVAr)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Active Power (MW) |
| MGVMU.CTRL | MGVMU RTU Control Input | Describes all the elements that the specific RTU can control. These are:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TAP Position&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capacitor State | [VVC.017] The MVGMU shall receive control signals from the SCADA as calculated by the VVC function (scenario 1)
[VVC.018] The MVGMU shall receive control signals from the VVC function directly (scenario 2)
[VVC.019] The MVGMU.RTU shall support the following control signals:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>TAP Position (number)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capacitor State (on/off per capacitor) |
| LVGMU.OUT | LVGMU Output measurements | Describes all the values measured and retrieved from the specific RTU. These are:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Line Capacitor Status&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Line Voltage Measurement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reactive Power&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Active Power | [VVC.020] The LVGMU.RTU shall provide its measurements to the SCADA (scenario 1)
[VVC.021] The LVGMU shall provide its measurements to the MVGMU (scenario 2)
[VVC.022] The measurements of the LVGMU.RTU shall be:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Line Capacitor Status (on/off flag)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Line Voltage (V)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reactive Power (MVAr)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Active Power (MW) |
| LVGMU.CTRL | LVGMU RTU Control Input | Describes all the elements that the specific RTU can control. These are:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Line Capacitor State&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Voltage Regulator set-point | [VVC.023] The LVGMU shall receive control signals from the SCADA as calculated by the VVC function (scenario 1)
[VVC.024] The LVGMU shall receive control signals from the MVGMU (scenario 2)
[VVC.025] The LGMU.RTU shall support the following control signals:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Capacitor State (on/off flag)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Live Voltage Regulator Set-Point (Power Factor) |
| DERMU.OUT | DERMU Output measurements | Describes all the values measured and retrieved from this unit. These are:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Voltage (RES)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Active Power (RES)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reactive Power (RES) | [VVC.026] The DERMU.RTU shall provide its measurements to the SCADA (scenario 1)
[VVC.027] The DERMU shall provide its measurements to the MVGMU (scenario 2)
[VVC.028] The measurements of the DERMU.RTU shall be:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Line Voltage (V)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reactive Power (MVAr)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Active Power (MW) |
| DERMU.CTRL | DERMU Control Input | Describes the controllable element of this unit which is: RES Set-Points. | [VVC.029] The DERMU shall receive control signals from the SCADA as calculated by the VVC function (scenario 1)
[VVC.030] The DERMU shall receive control signals from the MVGMU (scenario 2)
[VVC.031] The DERMU.RTU shall support the following control signals:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RES Set-Point (Power Factor per RES) |&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h1 id="7-common-terms-and-definitions">7. Common Terms and Definitions&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="8-custom-information-optional">8. Custom Information (optional)&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Key&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Value&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Refers to Section&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Docs: UC8</title><link>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/ebalance-plus/uc8/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/ebalance-plus/uc8/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="1-description-of-the-use-case">1. Description of the Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="11-name-of-the-use-case">1.1. Name of the Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>ID&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Area /Domain(s)/Zone(s)&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name of the Use Case&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>/ Distribution, DER / Station, Operation, Field, Process,&lt;/td>
&lt;td>UC8&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="12-version-management">1.2. Version Management&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Version No.&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Date&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name of author(s)&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Changes&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Approval status&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>v0.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2020-10-01T00:00:00&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Juan Jacobo Peralta,&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Preliminary description of narrative, objectives, users…&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="13-scope-and-objectives-of-use-case">1.3. Scope and Objectives of Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Scope&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>To enhance grid operation at distributed level by allowing flexibility mechanisms from Distributed Energy Resources (DER), specifically managing at district level Battery Energy Storage System (BESS), PV generation and V2G charging point infrastructure working on a DC voltage network.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Objective(s)&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>UC08.1. Balancing energy flows to support distribution grid operation (targets: charge/discharge electric vehicles, controlling local BESS and modulating PV production with power converters)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>UC08.2. Optimise electric car charging costs by local RES, local energy store or provided by the distribution grid (pool-based information)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>UC08.3. Reduce electric car charging CO2 emissions by using local RES, local energy store or provide by the distribution grid (pool-based information).&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>UC08.4. Demonstrate high-efficient operation of DC networks with silicon carbide-based power converters.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Related business case(s)&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Associated to UC.09 (DERMU role is exchanged with CMU role)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="14-narrative-of-use-case">1.4. Narrative of Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Short description&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Optimised control of DER (including PV generation, BESS and V2G) can help to release flexibility according to grid constraints to enhance its operation. This would lead to lower operational costs, grid congestion and generation curtailment, while maximising revenue through VPP services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Complete description&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This use case aims (a) to define technical solutions to manage the energy flexibility of distributed energy resources (DER) that are exploited potentially by a DER manager (e.g. facility manager, ESCO…), and (b) to define market steps to exploit such energy flexibility through energy aggregators, balance responsible parties (BRP) or similar stakeholders.
The technical context of this use case is a DC voltage network that integrates generation, storage and consumption units at district/neighbourhood level. As example, this use case is tested in the ebalance-plus project creating a DC voltage network with SiC-based power converters, PV canopies, external BESS and V2G infrastructure. In the operation level, the energy flow is managed mainly by two energy management units: the DERMU (distributed energy resources management unit) and the LVGMU (low voltage grid management unit). The former monitors the operation of all the DER components and receive the grid status and steering signals from the latter located in the secondary substation that supplies electricity to the DC network. As tentative market context, it is assumed that the DER manager has a deal with an energy retailer or energy aggregator to buy/sell the energy according to specific contract conditions (tariffs, daily prices, carbon emissions…) and with specific bonus by supporting grid operation.
The DERMU optimises energy flows considering the DC network components, energy forecasting (e.g. PV generation, charging vehicles, BESS status), energy contract conditions or requests on demand from the energy aggregator as primary scenario and it will balance energy flows when the LVGMU requests flexibility from the DSO/TSO level as alternative scenario.
In the primary scenario, the energy aggregator/ESCO enterprise system sends a specific flexibility request. The DERMU receives the steering signals, balances the network elements, and calculates the degree of compliance with the original requests and send it back to the aggregator/ESCO enterprise system, which validates if finally accepts the energy flexibility according to contractual conditions. In case of validation, the DERMU execute the optimized plan.
In the alternative scenario, the energy management system of DSO/TSO will request flexibility to the ebalance-plus platform. The MVGMUs identify the most suitable LVGMUs and generate specific steering signals. These in turn identifies the most suitable DERMU and generate specific steering signals to support the request in a cost-efficient manner. The DERMU receives the steering signals, balances the network elements, and calculates the degree of compliance with the original requests and send it back to the LVGMU. Finally, the energy retailer or energy aggregator accounting system monitors the flexibility released and calculates the bonus.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="15-key-performance-indicatiors-kpi">1.5. Key Performance Indicatiors (KPI)&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>ID&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Reference to mentioned use case objectives&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>I06b&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Ratio of local DER generation vs. local DER consumption (%)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Percentage of energy consumed by V2G infrastructure and energy losses (power conversion) regarding energy generation/storage. This indicator can be calculated under different time ranges (hour, day, week…)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>UC08.3,&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="16-use-case-conditions">1.6. Use case conditions&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Assumptions&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>UC8&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Prerequisites&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>UC8&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="17-further-information-to-the-use-case-for-classificationmapping">1.7. Further information to the use case for classification/mapping&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Relation to other use cases&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Level of depth&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Prioritisation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Mandatory&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Generic, regional or national relation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Generic&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Nature of the use cases&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Technical &amp;amp; Market&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Further keywords for classification&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Flexibility request, congestion, peak load reduction, DER optimization&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="18-general-remarks">1.8. General remarks&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>General remarks&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="2-diagrams-of-use-case">2. Diagrams of Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="Sequence_Diagram-Sc1.png" alt="Sequence diagram 1. Grid Capacity Management using available flexibility at DER domain">
&lt;img src="Sequence_Diagram-Sc2.png" alt="Sequence diagram 2. Aggregator flexibility management system requests flexibility">
&lt;img src="Component_layer.png" alt="SGAM - Component Layer">
&lt;img src="Function_layer.png" alt="SGAM - Function Layer">
&lt;img src="Communication_layer.png" alt="SGAM - Communication Layer">
&lt;img src="Information_layer.png" alt="SGAM - Information Layer">
&lt;img src="Buisness_layer.png" alt="SGAM - Buisness Layer">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="3-technical-details">3. Technical Details&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="31-actors">3.1. Actors&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Type&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Further information specific to this Use Case&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>ebalance-plus platform or TLGMU (top level grid management unit)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Grid management platform to balance energy according available flexibility&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>ebalance-plus platform: DERMU (Distributed Energy Resource Management Unit)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Electronic unit that manages all the energy operations at district level, optimise energy operation and manage energy flexibility.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>ebalance-plus platform: LVGMU (Low Voltage Grid Management Unit)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Electronic unit that manages all the energy operations of management units (CMU/DERMU) connected to their secondary substation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>ebalance-plus platform: MVGMU (Low Voltage Grid Management Unit)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Electronic unit that manages all the energy operations of management units (LVGMU/DERMU) connected to their secondary substation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Energy aggregator flexibility management system&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>SW that support energy aggregator to make decisions about flexibility management&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>DSO energy management system&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>SW that support DSO to establish grid capacity thresholds in PS/SS&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>EV-V2G user&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Role&lt;/td>
&lt;td>EV user&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>DER Manager&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Role&lt;/td>
&lt;td>User that establishes operation preferences for its DER facility&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>V2G charging points EMS&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Integrated EMS in the V2G charging points&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>District BESS&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>External BESS supporting DER flexibility&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Local RES Power Converter EMS (e.g. PV)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Power converter manages energy flows from local RES&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="32-references">3.2. References&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>References Type&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Reference&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Status&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Impact on Use Case&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Organistaor / Organisation&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Link&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="4-step-by-step-analysis-of-use-case">4. Step by Step Analysis of Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="41-overview-of-scenarios">4.1. Overview of Scenarios&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Primary Actor&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Triggering Event&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Pre-Condition&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Post-Condition&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>PS1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Grid Capacity Management using available flexibility at DER domain (success)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Some grid management unit of the ebalance-plus platform detect a forthcoming threshold overpass and calculate the necessary flexibility and request this flexibility to the corresponding DERMU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Grid Capacity Management using available flexibility at DER domain (success)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>PS2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Aggregator flexibility management system requests flexibility&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Some energy aggregator flexibility system requests to ebalance-plus platform flexibility balancing services. The ebalance-plus identifies the DERMUs registered to the corresponding aggregator and activate flexibility services.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Aggregator flexibility management system requests flexibility&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>AS1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Grid Capacity Management using available flexibility at DER domain (failure)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Some grid management unit of the ebalance-plus platform detect a forthcoming threshold overpass and calculate the necessary flexibility and request this flexibility to the corresponding DERMU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Grid Capacity Management using available flexibility at DER domain (failure)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Notes&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="42-steps--scenarios">4.2. Steps – Scenarios&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Grid Capacity Management using available flexibility at DER domain (success)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Periodic execution&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The MVGMU/LVMGU located at PS/SS respectively receives power load forecasting (external/internal service)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Estimation of steady state&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Verification of DSO’s load thresholds and dispatching flexibility requests to lower units (economic dispatching based on operational constraints)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Evaluation of flexibility request&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The DERMU optimizes the DER energy profile to meet flexibility requests and evaluate the compliance. It generates the steering signals (set points) to the DER units.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Compliance check&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>DER’s EMS check &amp;amp; confirm flexibility level compliance (new energy profile)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy profile aggregation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>DERMU aggregates energy profile from DER units and send back to the LVGMU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy profile aggregation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>LVGMU aggregates energy profile from DER units and send back to the MVGMU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.5&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Publish&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>DERMU published energy flexibility released&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Update load forecasting&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>LVGMU update load forecasting and run new steady state to verify load thresholds&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REPORT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Update load forecasting&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>MVGMU update load forecasting and run new steady state to verify load thresholds&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REPORT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Validation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>LVGMU/MVGMU meet DSO’s thresholds and established state condition in normal operation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REPORT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Aggregator flexibility management system requests flexibility&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Execution on demand&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The external flexibility management system request flexibility (energy profile) to their DER customers.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REPORT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Dispatching flexibility to DERMU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Dispatching flexibility requests to DER linked to the energy aggregator&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Evaluation of flexibility request&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The DERMU optimizes the DER energy profile to meet flexibility requests and evaluate the compliance. It generates the steering signals (set points) to the DER units.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Compliance check&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>DER’s EMS check &amp;amp; confirm flexibility level compliance (new energy profile)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy profile aggregation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>DERMU aggregates energy profile from DER units and send back to the TLGMU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy profile aggregation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>TLGMU aggregates energy profile from DER units and send back to the Aggregator flexibility management system&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Register&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>TLGMU registers energy flexibility released&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Grid Capacity Management using available flexibility at DER domain (failure)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Periodic execution&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The MVGMU/LVMGU located at PS/SS respectively receives power load forecasting (external/internal service)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Estimation of steady state&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Verification of DSO’s load thresholds and dispatching flexibility requests to lower units (economic dispatching based on operational constraints)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Evaluation of flexibility request&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The DERMU optimizes the DER energy profile to meet flexibility requests and evaluate the compliance. It generates the steering signals (set points) to the DER units.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Compliance check&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>DER’s EMS check &amp;amp; confirm flexibility level compliance (new energy profile)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy profile aggregation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>DERMU aggregates energy profile from DER units and send back to the LVGMU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy profile aggregation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>LVGMU aggregates energy profile from DER units and send back to the MVGMU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.5&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Publish&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>DERMU published energy flexibility released&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Update load forecasting&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>LVGMU update load forecasting and run new steady state to verify load thresholds&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REPORT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Update load forecasting&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>MVGMU update load forecasting and run new steady state to verify load thresholds&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REPORT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Validation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>LVGMU/MVGMU cannot meet DSO’s thresholds, activates alternative strategies (see grid management use cases)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REPORT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="5-information-exchanged">5. Information Exchanged&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information exchanged ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Information&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirement&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="6-requirements-optional">6. Requirements (optional)&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Category Identifier&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>mRID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Req_ID&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Req_Name&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&amp;lsquo;Flexibility measures I: Virtual Power Plant (VPP) services based on district solutions (variable PV generation, storage and V2G)&amp;rsquo;&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Identifier&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>mRID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>VPP.EP&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy profile&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Array with energy values (positive/negative) indicating the consumption/generation status&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>VPP.FR&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Flexibility requests&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Array with min/max power values (positive/negative) and periods indicating the requested energy flexibility&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress (e.g. based on USEF recommendations)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>PP.AFR&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Actual flexibility released&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Array with power values (positive/negative) and periods indicating the released energy flexibility&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress (e.g. based on USEF recommendations)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="7-common-terms-and-definitions">7. Common Terms and Definitions&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="8-custom-information-optional">8. Custom Information (optional)&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Key&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Value&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Refers to Section&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Docs: UC9</title><link>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/ebalance-plus/uc9/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://smart-grid-use-cases.github.io/docs/usecases/ebalance-plus/uc9/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="1-description-of-the-use-case">1. Description of the Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="11-name-of-the-use-case">1.1. Name of the Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>ID&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Area /Domain(s)/Zone(s)&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name of the Use Case&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>/ Customer premise, Distribution / Station, Operation, Field, Process, Enterprise,&lt;/td>
&lt;td>UC9&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="12-version-management">1.2. Version Management&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Version No.&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Date&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name of author(s)&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Changes&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Approval status&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>v0.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>2020-10-01T00:00:00&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Juan Jacobo Peralta,&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Preliminary description of narrative, objectives, users…&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="13-scope-and-objectives-of-use-case">1.3. Scope and Objectives of Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Scope&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>To enhance grid operation at the distribution level by allowing flexibility mechanisms from Building Energy Management including Battery Energy Storage System (BESS), PV generation and IoT devices.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Objective(s)&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>UC09.1. Balancing energy flows to support distribution grid operation (lower operational costs, reducing grid congestion and minimizing generation curtailment).&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>UC09.2. Optimising BEM operation including control of smart devices (IoT), roof-PV generation and batteries.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>UC09.3. Reducing energy consumption costs and/or CO2 emissions at building level.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>UC09.4. Encouraging different actors (facility managers, DSOs/TSOs or energy aggregators) to request/release flexibility through the ebalance-plus platform.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Related business case(s)&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Associated to UC.08 (CMU role is exchanged with DERMU role)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="14-narrative-of-use-case">1.4. Narrative of Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Short description&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Buildings accounts for 40% of the final energy consumption in Europe and its flexibility is seen as one of the most relevant means to manage future grids and enhance their operation. This would lead to lower operational costs, grid congestion and generation curtailment, while maximising revenue through VPP services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Complete description&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="15-key-performance-indicatiors-kpi">1.5. Key Performance Indicatiors (KPI)&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>ID&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Name&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Reference to mentioned use case objectives&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>I06a&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Ratio of local production with flexible solutions (kWh produced vs consumed) (%)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Percentage of energy consumed by building facilities (smart devices) regarding energy generation/storage. This indicator can be calculated under different time ranges (hour, day, week…).&lt;/td>
&lt;td>UC09.2,&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="16-use-case-conditions">1.6. Use case conditions&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Assumptions&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>UC9&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Prerequisites&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>UC9&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="17-further-information-to-the-use-case-for-classificationmapping">1.7. Further information to the use case for classification/mapping&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Relation to other use cases&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Level of depth&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Prioritisation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Mandatory&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Generic, regional or national relation&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Generic&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Nature of the use cases&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Technical &amp;amp; Market&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>Further keywords for classification&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Flexibility request, congestion, peak load reduction, BEMS optimization&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="18-general-remarks">1.8. General remarks&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>General remarks&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="2-diagrams-of-use-case">2. Diagrams of Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="Sequence_Diagram-Sc1.png" alt="Sequence diagram 1. Grid Capacity Management using available flexibility at DER domain">
&lt;img src="Sequence_Diagram-Sc2.png" alt="Sequence diagram 2. Aggregator flexibility management system requests flexibility">
&lt;img src="Component_layer.png" alt="SGAM - Component Layer">
&lt;img src="Function_layer.png" alt="SGAM - Function Layer">
&lt;img src="Communication_layer.png" alt="SGAM - Communication Layer">
&lt;img src="Information_layer.png" alt="SGAM - Information Layer">
&lt;img src="Buisness_layer.png" alt="SGAM - Buisness Layer">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="3-technical-details">3. Technical Details&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="31-actors">3.1. Actors&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Type&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Actor Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Further information specific to this Use Case&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>ebalance-plus platform or TLGMU (Top Level Grid Management Unit)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Grid management platform to balance energy according to available flexibility&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>ebalance-plus platform: CMU (Customer Management Unit)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Electronic unit that manages all the energy operations at building level, optimise energy operation and manage energy flexibility.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>ebalance-plus platform: LVGMU (Low Voltage Grid Management Unit)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Electronic unit that manages all the energy operations of management units (CMU/DERMU) connected to their secondary substation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>ebalance-plus platform: MVGMU (Low Voltage Grid Management Unit)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Electronic unit that manages all the energy operations of management units (LVGMU/DERMU) connected to their secondary substation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Energy aggregator flexibility management system&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>SW that support energy aggregator to make decisions about flexibility management&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>DSO energy management system&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>SW that support DSO to establish grid capacity thresholds in PS/SS&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Facility Manager&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Role&lt;/td>
&lt;td>A physical client of a DSO that is involved at Demo scale.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>BEMS&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Building Energy Management System.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Building facility component&lt;/td>
&lt;td>System&lt;/td>
&lt;td>All devices working on electricity that can be found in a customer&amp;rsquo;s dwelling.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Customer&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Role&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Dwelling’s inhabitant / customer&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="32-references">3.2. References&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>References Type&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Reference&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Status&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Impact on Use Case&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Organistaor / Organisation&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Link&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="4-step-by-step-analysis-of-use-case">4. Step by Step Analysis of Use Case&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="41-overview-of-scenarios">4.1. Overview of Scenarios&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Primary Actor&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Triggering Event&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Pre-Condition&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Post-Condition&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>PS1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Grid Capacity Management using available flexibility at Customer premise domain (success)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Some grid management unit of the ebalance-plus platform (MVGMU / LVGMU) detects a forthcoming threshold overpass and calculate the necessary flexibility and request this flexibility to the corresponding CMU.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Grid Capacity Management using available flexibility at Customer premise domain (success)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>PS2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Aggregator flexibility management system requests flexibility&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Some energy aggregator flexibility system requests to ebalance-plus platform flexibility balancing services. The ebalance-plus identifies the CMUs registered to the corresponding aggregator (authentication) and activate flexibility services.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Aggregator flexibility management system requests flexibility&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>AS1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Grid Capacity Management using available flexibility at Customer premise domain (failure)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Some grid management unit of the ebalance-plus platform (MVGMU / LVGMU) detects a forthcoming threshold overpass and calculate the necessary flexibility and request this flexibility to the corresponding CMU.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Grid Capacity Management using available flexibility at Customer premise domain (failure)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Notes&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="42-steps--scenarios">4.2. Steps – Scenarios&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Grid Capacity Management using available flexibility at Customer premise domain (success)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Periodic execution&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The MVGMU/LVMGU located at PS/SS respectively receives power load forecasting (external/internal service)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Estimation of steady state&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Verification of DSO’s load thresholds and dispatching flexibility requests to lower units (Optimal Power Flow)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Evaluation of flexibility request&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The CMU optimizes the building facility energy profile to meet flexibility requests and evaluate the compliance. It generates the steering signals (set points) to the building facilities.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress. Minimum resolution should be 15 minutes.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Compliance check&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>BEMS check &amp;amp; confirm flexibility level compliance (new energy profile)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress. Minimum resolution should be 15 minutes.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy profile aggregation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CMU aggregates energy profile from building facilities and send back to the LVGMU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress. Minimum resolution should be 15 minutes.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy profile aggregation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>LVGMU aggregates energy profile from CMUs and send back to the MVGMU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress. Minimum resolution should be 15 minutes.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.5&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Publish&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CMU publishes energy flexibility released&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress. Minimum resolution should be 15 minutes.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Update load forecasting&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>LVGMU update load forecasting and run new steady state to verify load thresholds&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REPORT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Update load forecasting&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>MVGMU update load forecasting and run new steady state to verify load thresholds&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REPORT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Validation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>LVGMU/MVGMU meet DSO’s thresholds and established state condition in normal operation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REPORT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Aggregator flexibility management system requests flexibility&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Execution on demand&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The external flexibility management systems request flexibility (energy profile) to their customers (facility managers).&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REPORT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Dispatching flexibility to CMU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Dispatching flexibility requests to the CMUs linked to the energy aggregator&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Evaluation of flexibility request&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The CMU optimizes the building facility energy profile to meet flexibility requests and evaluate the compliance. It generates the steering signals (set points) to the building facilities.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress. Minimum resolution should be 15 minutes.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Compliance check&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>BEMS check &amp;amp; confirm flexibility level compliance (new energy profile)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress. Minimum resolution should be 15 minutes.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy profile aggregation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CMU aggregates energy profile from building facilities and send back to the TLGMU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress. Minimum resolution should be 15 minutes.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy profile aggregation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>TLGMU aggregates energy profile from building facilities and send back to the Aggregator flexibility management system&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress. Minimum resolution should be 15 minutes.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Register&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>TLGMU registers energy flexibility released&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Update load forecasting&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>LVGMU update load forecasting and run new steady state to verify load thresholds&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REPORT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Update load forecasting&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>MVGMU update load forecasting and run new steady state to verify load thresholds&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REPORT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Scenario Name:&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Grid Capacity Management using available flexibility at Customer premise domain (failure)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Step No.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Event.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Process/ Activity&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Process/ Activity.&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Producer (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Receiver (Actor)&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirements, R-ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Periodic execution&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The MVGMU/LVMGU located at PS/SS respectively receives power load forecasting (external/internal service)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>GET&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>1.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Estimation of steady state&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Verification of DSO’s load thresholds and dispatching flexibility requests to lower units (Optimal Power Flow)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Evaluation of flexibility request&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The CMU optimizes the building facility energy profile to meet flexibility requests and evaluate the compliance. It generates the steering signals (set points) to the building facilities.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress. Minimum resolution should be 15 minutes.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Compliance check&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>BEMS check &amp;amp; confirm flexibility level compliance (new energy profile)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress. Minimum resolution should be 15 minutes.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.3&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy profile aggregation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CMU aggregates energy profile from building facilities and send back to the LVGMU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress. Minimum resolution should be 15 minutes.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy profile aggregation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>LVGMU aggregates energy profile from building facilities and send back to the MVGMU&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress. Minimum resolution should be 15 minutes.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>2.5&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Publish&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CMU publishes energy flexibility released&lt;/td>
&lt;td>CREATE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3.1&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Update load forecasting&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>LVGMU update load forecasting and run new steady state to verify load thresholds&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REPORT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>3.2&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Update load forecasting&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>MVGMU update load forecasting and run new steady state to verify load thresholds&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REPORT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>4&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Validation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None&lt;/td>
&lt;td>LVGMU/MVGMU cannot meet DSO’s thresholds, activates alternative strategies (see grid management use cases)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>REPORT&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="5-information-exchanged">5. Information Exchanged&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Information exchanged ID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name of Information&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description of Information Exchanged&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Requirement&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="6-requirements-optional">6. Requirements (optional)&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Category Identifier&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>mRID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Req_ID&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Req_Name&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&amp;lsquo;Flexibility measures II: Virtual Power Plant (VPP) services based on building solutions (IoT devices, PV and storage)&amp;rsquo;&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Identifier&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Name&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Description&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>mRID&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>VPP.EP&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Energy profile&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Array with energy values (positive/negative) indicating the consumption/generation status&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress. Minimum resolution should be 15 minutes.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>VPP.FR&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Flexibility requests&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Array with min/max power values (positive/negative) and periods indicating the requested energy flexibility&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress (e.g., based on USEF recommendations)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>PP.AFR&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Actual flexibility released&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Array with power values (positive/negative) and periods indicating the released energy flexibility&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The structure of this data will be decided during project progress (e.g., based on USEF recommendations)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h1 id="7-common-terms-and-definitions">7. Common Terms and Definitions&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="8-custom-information-optional">8. Custom Information (optional)&lt;/h1>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Key&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Value&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>Refers to Section&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;/table></description></item></channel></rss>